DM: It worked out story-wise quite well
Unknown: Yeah, it was, yeah, it was great
DM: He might've been less friendly if you had just one from the beginning
Unknown: Yeah, it, it worked out the way it was
DM: It was Seeker strategy unintentionally.
DM: [laughs]
DM: Um, okay, so
DM: over the course of the next two hours you invisibly make your way across the landscape to the eaves of the forests.
DM: Um,
DM: you do see one pair of dragonets flying overhead, but they do not see you, as you are invisible.
DM: They seem to be heading south and unlikely to be related to any of your doings.
DM: Um,
DM: and the terrain, you know, so as you get further from the city the, the manors spread out.
DM: You pass a couple more of these, um,
DM: those things that look like
Unknown: possibly ancient tent sites with-
Unknown: Is this yours or...?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Okay. I'm doing my duty
DM: ... with these arcane circles.
DM: Um,
DM: there's no, there isn't any-
Unknown: Gotta protect
DM: You don't pass anything that looks like farmland, although of course ancient farmland, if it was farmland thousands of years ago, would be overgrown.
DM: But it seems, it seems very dry.
Unknown: Like, there's no rivers, there's no water anywhere.
DM: There's har- oh, like only the occasional spring, so this is like scrub.
DM: It's like sort of very little,
DM: um-
Seeker: The forests are trapping the rivers
DM: Very few,
DM: uh, plants grow, just like little scrubby grasses and things.
DM: Um, the only animals that you see regularly are like little lizards that are s- scurrying around eating bugs.
DM: But as you, so as you approach,
DM: so it's a pretty smooth journey.
DM: I mean, the terrain's not that difficult to navigate.
DM: Um,
DM: you can see the forest getting closer.
DM: You, you reach the edge of the forest just about where the pilgrim's path that comes from the north enters the forest
Unknown: Right
DM: And you, I mean, you can see the road from some distance off, right?
DM: It's just as nice as the other road you passed.
DM: And
DM: so the forest itself, um, it's, at least here it's fairly open and airy and light, and the sun is shining.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, it's, it's not...
DM: It's sort of tall,
DM: sort of jungly trees, but
DM: light. Like, there's a lot of light coming through.
DM: There's like flowers growing in the under- understory.
DM: It's not like a real rainforest where you've got this closed canopy and then it's like really dense beneath, right?
DM: It's a pretty open
DM: forest. Um,
DM: but still when you s- I mean, when you step inside at 7:00, like you know, sun- sun sets quickly in the tropics, and you know, it's already start, the light is starting to get low, and so
DM: there's long shadows that are kind of cast across the, the,
DM: you know, the few open clearings that you pass through.
DM: Um, and you can actually see, so the, the pilgrim's path, you can see it goes straight,
DM: you know, kind of through the forest for,
DM: um,
DM: you know, for a while. Like, for
DM: a few miles anyway.
DM: You can... But it's like looking up like a cleared road, right?
DM: So there's no, there's trees that sort of form a canopy above it, but there's nothing growing on the road.
DM: There's no like sprouts sticking up.
DM: There's no roots that are disrupting the pavement, so it's like a very, you can't see very far in any other direction.
DM: But you can see
DM: quite far in that distance.
DM: And, and what you f- what you see is like it comes after maybe five or six miles,
DM: it sort of meets, it begins to like s- like it turns, and you can't see how it turns, but it looks like it joins with all the, probably your guess is it joins with all the other paths and it begins to sort
DM: of spiral up the mountain.
DM: But this now is, because it's not a straight path, right, we can't see it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um,
DM: but otherwise, like the, the forest is, I mean, there's some birdsong.
DM: Like, there's the sound of buzzing insects at this time of day with the hot sun.
DM: It's pretty warm.
DM: You don't hear any, like, owls singing or anything.
DM: So where do you wanna go?
Unknown: Follow the road in from there?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. I think we get on-
Seeker: Oh, we use, um, our jade direction sense presumably?
Unknown: But we know where the jade is. It's not there.
DM: The jade, the jade's in the lair
Unknown: Oh, oh, oh. I thought we were trying to help.
Unknown: We're talking about the elders.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: No, no, no. We went into, we're going to try and find-
Unknown: Oh, sorry
Delwath: ... check out the monastery and see if we can find the elder dragonet, AKA Divitar
Unknown: AKA Divitar. Got it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: let's just walk on the path
Unknown: No longer invisible?
Delwath: Yeah. Once we come into the forest.
Delwath: But actually we haven't been invisible for a little bit.
DM: Yeah, for a couple miles
Delwath: 'Cause I only did it, it covered eight of the 10 miles invisible.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But we were long off the, like,
Unknown: flight path by the time it disappeared
Unknown: 'Cause the dragonets don't come into the forest.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: So.
Delwath: Yeah. Or yeah, let's just walk
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: so, so you walk along the path.
DM: it's actually quite easy walking.
DM: It almost feels like you're-
Unknown: Hold on.
DM: Yeah
Unknown: How
Unknown: well,
Delwath: if I asked my wings to go bring a message to the elder, the eldest dragonet
DM: You have to at least be able to describe the person.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: You don't have to, like, know their name or anything.
Unknown: It can't just be everywhere.
DM: It can't just be everywhere.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: Does it have to be something you've seen?
Delwath: No, but just an actual...
Delwath: Somebody who had met... If I had a description from somebody who had met this dragonet, then I could.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: But you've seen a vision of it.
Kenzo: Or I've seen a vision of it.
Delwath: Have we connected in game your vision with this?
Kenzo: Yeah. Maybe.
Seeker: Well, we don't... We certainly don't know for sure that it's the same creature.
DM: Maybe. But-
Kenzo: I mean, when in the vision it was a...
Kenzo: It was literally one of these creatures, but, like, old looking.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: It was a pretty unusual type of creature, so.
Kenzo: Also hanging with the fucking, like, wizard guy that's, like, in my dr- Like, that's-
Delwath: Can I, can I send a message to the person that Rai describes to me and from his vision?
Delwath: Or did we all see that? Did we all see one of those visions?
DM: No, it was Rai's dream. It was Kenzo's dream of Rai.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: To me.
DM: Um,
DM: I [laughs]...
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I don't know. Maybe.
DM: I mean-
Kenzo: No, this, this is pretty reasonable.
Kenzo: It's like, I mean, 'cause it's like
Kenzo: the one that I saw in the vision was, like, an old one of these, right?
Kenzo: And the one that we just saw was like 17 years old.
Kenzo: Like, were there any, like, old looking one?
Kenzo: Oh, one thing I should ask them, or maybe I did ask them, is like, you know, how old do they live, typically live to?
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: The dragonets.
DM: Um, they don't, I mean they, they, they're sort of like human-ish lifespans.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: Typically. Maybe a little shorter.
Kenzo: Wait, but Dimitar would be super old.
DM: Would be super, super old.
Kenzo: But was he magical? He was, right?
DM: Yeah, like Rai's familiar.
Kenzo: Oh.
DM: Seeker.
Seeker: Di- yeah, Dimitar would be 200 something right?
Kenzo: Could he, like, cast spells and do shit? What did he do other than, like, be a pain in the ass?
DM: Mostly he just, like, was a pain in the ass.
DM: [laughing]
Kenzo: That's what I thought, right? He was kind of a pain in the ass.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Yeah, aren't familiars supposed to be, like, useful and do, like, useful things?
DM: Well, Rai made a bad choice, I guess.
DM: [laughing]
Kenzo: Must be counterbalance for Rai, I guess.
Kenzo: Or, like, ultra powerful, but...
DM: I think it's a little too meta game.
Kenzo: What?
Kenzo: No, but, well, no, no, but I actually don't, right?
Kenzo: 'Cause it's like the only time we've seen...
Kenzo: Like it would, it would've clicked for Kenzo that the only time we've ever seen, like, any of these things before is in this vision with the drag- With, with, um...
Kenzo: And if this guy's talking about an elder...
Seeker: But it's just like Kenzo's gotta describe this particular creature to Delwath, and then describes the creature-
Kenzo: To the links
Unknown: ... to
Unknown: the links.
Kenzo: Yeah, that might be too much. But I think, I, I don't think the c- like, our characters...
Kenzo: I think it'd be reasonable for us to guess that the-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... that the-
DM: But the, I mean, the intent is not to be able to determine whether somebody is real or not by sending them messages with that.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: That,
Kenzo: that's fair.
Unknown: Right.
DM: That's right.
Kenzo: That's fair.
Unknown: That's a fair point.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: So I don't think you can use it to send a message to somebody who might exist or might be close by,
DM: right? The intent is to use it to send messages to people you know exist.
Wellby: How far can you scan for consciousnesses?
Kenzo: 30 mile.
Kenzo: Anywhere on the island.
Wellby: Can you look across the whole wood to see if there's, like-
Kenzo: You know, that's actually interesting.
Kenzo: Could I, could... That actually would, I potentially could do, would be to try to suss out the specific, um,
Kenzo: aura of a sp- Actually, that's what it's for.
Wellby: Right.
Kenzo: I could try to, I could, I could, I could try to find the elder, the elder, um.
DM: Um, yep.
Unknown: Mm. Mm.
DM: You'd have to spend another 6 ki, so it's, it's getting...
DM: Well, you could always take a short rest.
Kenzo: Yeah. Why don't I short rest real quick?
Unknown: Let's walk for a little bit.
Kenzo: The whole thing? But no.
Unknown: Let's mope.
Kenzo: Like, if I can find Dimitar now, like I'll just know where he is.
Wellby: If you know where any, like, sentient being in the forest is.
Kenzo: Actually-
DM: Well, you have to have q- Like you can either get a general sense or you have to search for a specific-
Kenzo: Short... How long is a short rest?
Unknown: An hour.
DM: An hour.
Kenzo: I, right now I've still got like nine ki or whatever, so how about, how about I do, um...
Kenzo: Yeah, just I'll, I'll, I'll do a, a search in the forest specifically for, um, looking for the energy, actually over the whole island actually, specifically looking for the energy
Kenzo: of an elder, the oldest bit dragonet energy-
DM: Okay
Kenzo: ... on the pl- on this, this island.
DM: Mm.
DM: Um, in the monastery on the top of the mountain.
Kenzo: Wow.
Unknown: Huh.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah.
Wellby: All right. Let's hustle.
Unknown: Are we going up?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Now can I send... I mean,
Delwath: I don't know if I actually want to send a message or what we would say.
Kenzo: Well, n- n- now I know, we know exactly where he is now.
Delwath: But we should be able to send a message knowing-
DM: Yes. Now you could send a message.
Unknown: Should we send a message ahead?
Kenzo: To say what?
DM: So you walk, as you talk, you walk along the forest road.
DM: And again, like I was saying, it, it feels
DM: almost as if your pace is quickened by the road you're walking on.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And you're covering ground surprisingly fast as the sun sets.
DM: Over the course of about an hour, the sun sinks.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Sunset lights up the sky,
DM: and you hear to the right of the path, so west, as you're heading to the mountain, what sounds like the
DM: sound of running water
DM: and a waterfall.
DM: Keep walking? [laughs]
Kenzo: Last time we didn't investigate the waterfall.
DM: Continue-
Delwath: No, I think, I, I think I am gonna send the links ahead with a message to this creature saying...
Kenzo: Saying what?
Unknown: Um, "We're
Unknown: coming to visit.
Unknown: Are there dangers?"
Kenzo: We could be a danger.
Kenzo: That's why we, we wanna like-
DM: Should you mention Rai maybe?
DM: Or coming.
Unknown: We can say who we are
DM: I'm trying to follow Rai's mission
Delwath: We're, we're, we're, we're seeking, we're coming...
Unknown: I just feel like we should announce ourselves.
Unknown: They can't fly away.
Kenzo: But like...
Delwath: And like we don't know is, is,
Delwath: is this creature like tra- I mean, your detection doesn't tell us anything about-
Kenzo: No, no
Unknown: ... right?
Kenzo: But I'll, but I'll, okay. But okay, I mean, I think it would be reasonable for, for us in game to be like, "Hey, this is like the thing."
Kenzo: But like, I would wanna wait to like,
Kenzo: like converse with it more when we see it, you know?
Delwath: See, I wanna find out if it is
Delwath: able to converse or like trapped by some evil monster.
Kenzo: Okay. Okay.
Seeker: As we get closer, I can clairvoyance also.
Kenzo: Yeah, that feels useful. That feels more useful.
DM: But then-
Unknown: Maybe we clairvoyance first
Wellby: I think 'cause it's, it's like the one way nature of the message just makes it difficult.
Kenzo: Yeah. 'Cause then we, we don't know, like-
Unknown: We can send a response
Wellby: But like we can't anticipate-
Unknown: Yes, I know
Wellby: ... all the possible situations that it might be.
Kenzo: Let's get closer and clairvoyance
Unknown: No, that's actually better
DM: You're, you're about eight miles away right now from the summit of the mountain.
Kenzo: What's the range for clairvoyance?
Seeker: Well, technically one, and then I can double it up to five times burning all my slots that I'm gonna need for other spells
Kenzo: Yeah, don't do that
Unknown: Wow. I would double it
Unknown: once maybe.
DM: So we'll do it at, at a two mile range?
Unknown: At two miles out.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Yeah, I was thinking like a similar thing, yeah.
DM: So you keep walking into the night and you actually like feel
DM: the, the, it, you almost feel as if there's many other people walking with you and you sort of have a feeling like
DM: the traditional sort of pilgrim's route was to walk through the night and reach the summit of the
DM: mountain at dawn.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: And every now and then you do hear sort of like whispers.
DM: It almost sounds like the wind rustling to the trees sounds almost elvish.
Unknown: What, what did the elves have to do with these human goddamn?
Delwath: The elves, as far as I know, the elves had nothing to do with these people.
Kenzo: Then what the fuck are they doing all up in this?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: So you keep walking as the darkness sets and the moon rises.
Kenzo: Once we get to two miles away, let's clairvoyance inside.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah, I think so.
DM: So another-
Unknown: Mark those off
DM: ... um, another, another, you know,
DM: hour or so-
Delwath: So, so like 8:00 at night
DM: ... walking, it's like 8:00 at night, um,
DM: uh, you pass again,
DM: um,
DM: a place where, um, a stream seems to flow like on the right side, or sorry, on the left side now 'cause the east seems to s- s- flow close to the, very close to
Unknown: the, the, um, the road.
Delwath: Does the, does the forest keep going up the mountain or-
DM: About halfway up the mountain
Unknown: Okay. So we're still in the forest.
DM: You're still in the... You haven't hit the part where it spirals yet.
DM: When-
Kenzo: And is the stream, and the, is the stream flowing up or down?
DM: Down, but it's stopped.
DM: Like it's stopped.
DM: You can see it flowing and it stops.
DM: And by the side of the,
DM: by the side of the road, there's this big pool which the stream flows into, but doesn't exit from.
Kenzo: Huh. Should I go to the pool real quick?
DM: Um,
DM: okay, hold on. Sorry.
Unknown: I, I have to do something.
Unknown: Roll initiative.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: God, I can't wait to roll my plus 10 initiative.
Unknown: With advantage, right?
Kenzo: With advantage, yeah. That's crazy.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, you walk, you walk over to the pool,
DM: um,
DM: and as you get closer, you see that the,
DM: the water is kind of murky and filled with like debris.
DM: And there's two stones that are sort of standing next to it, like sort of an entryway to a little viewing area over the pool that are actually cracked.
DM: One has fallen in half and part of the stone has, um, fallen into the pool itself.
DM: And you can see staring out at you from the pool, like the reflections of people with hollow eyes,
DM: their faces contorted in pain.
DM: Make a wisdom saving throw.
Unknown: Everybody or just-
DM: Just Kenzo. He's the only one who's
Delwath: [laughs] Well, I don't know. I was thinking we might have all followed him, but I guess not.
Delwath: [laughs] Thanks for being the, um, guinea pig, Kenzo.
Kenzo: Plus eight.
Kenzo: Wait, and also I get to, I get, um, advantage, right?
DM: From what?
Kenzo: Oh, I guess I can just roll this.
DM: You can roll a-
Kenzo: I can use my heroic
DM: ... if you want. Yeah
Kenzo: ... my heroic, uh, whatever.
Unknown: Oh, fuck. I forget which one. I'm gonna try this one.
Kenzo: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Nice.
Kenzo: 26.
Kenzo: Oh, sorry.
DM: You feel a bit uneasy, but nothing bad happens to you.
Kenzo: 24. Wait, sorry.
Kenzo: So I see the reflections of these, these like, like tortured souls or whatever in the thing, but there's no...
Kenzo: It's, I'm just seeing their reflections.
DM: You're just seeing the reflections. There's nothing standing around the pool.
Kenzo: Do I sense anything standing around the pool?
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: Um, do I have the heebie-jeebies?
DM: Yeah, a little bit.
Kenzo: Did I have the heebie-jeebies before?
DM: No.
DM: I mean, it's a creepy image, right?
DM: It's like people who died in pain looking back up at you and kind of screaming at you.
Delwath: But they're not underwater looking up, they're reflections?
Unknown: Is it-
DM: They seem like they're reflections, yeah
Kenzo: Do they look like they're... So they don't look like they're trapped in there.
Kenzo: They look like they're standing around the pool, but I just can't see them.
DM: Exactly. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And, uh, do they look like they were, um, like what, what was the way in which they died?
Kenzo: Were they, do they like have like battle wounds and stuff, or do they look like sickly, um-
DM: Sickly
Kenzo: Almost as though like a demonic red mist may have
DM: Kind of something like that, yes
Kenzo: Interesting. Okay.
Unknown: So the fucking plague mist came here.
Seeker: Does this feel like a dispel magic situation?
DM: That's up to you.
Kenzo: So yeah, don't look at that.
Kenzo: Um.
Unknown: Keep going?
DM: Keep going.
Delwath: I think keep going.
Delwath: Cleansing the island is sort of a bigger task than-
Unknown: Yeah, we don't want
Unknown: to do it
Kenzo: Oh, actually, you know, um, can I do cleansing touch to this thing?
DM: You wanna touch the water?
Kenzo: I mean, hold on. I, I mean, I can-
Delwath: The right answer when the GM says a question like that with that tone of voice is 100% of the time, "No, no, no, I don't."
Kenzo: Oh. [laughs]
DM: You have to touch somebody to do cleansing touch.
Kenzo: Yeah, cleansing touch is touching a creature.
DM: I mean, you could try it, but you'd have to touch the water for it to have any effect.
Delwath: I mean, bad ideas can be fun.
Kenzo: I don't know. I'll, I'll touch the water later.
DM: Okay. [laughs] So you ke- you keep going and, and you're now-
Unknown: We'll get that on the way back
DM: ... another-
Kenzo: All right. I will though
DM: ... um, it's another, uh,
DM: mile or so as you, the pa- the road begins to like go slightly up, um, and you can see about, um, half a mile ahead is the place where it curved that
DM: you can't, you couldn't see beyond.
DM: Forest is still open, the moonlight is shining down.
DM: Um,
DM: another like stream with another pool.
DM: This seems to be like all of the water that flows down off the mountain stops in this pool.
Kenzo: Right. Are we about two miles away yet?
DM: Um, at this point, yeah.
DM: I mean, the, the road is longer than two miles from here, but the-
Unknown: Straight off is two miles
DM: ... straight off is about two miles, yeah.
Kenzo: Fabulous.
Wellby: As we were coming in, was there any evidence of past stream beds?
Unknown: In other words,
Wellby: did the water used to flow all the way across the island and now it doesn't?
DM: Doesn't, you didn't see anything like that.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: This island is hollow probably.
DM: Um, Wellby's-
Kenzo: There's legs, there's legs at the bottom
DM: ... of course, now he wants to look at the other pool
Kenzo: For what it...
Unknown: What's that?
DM: Nobody wants to look at the other pool
Wellby: Kenzo, there's another pool to look at.
Delwath: Would you like to go check it out?
Kenzo: I think I know what's inside there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right.
DM: Clairvoyance?
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: yeah, so I'll use one glove charge
Unknown: and
Seeker: cast, what level is clairvoyance?
Seeker: Third, one, third level slot.
Unknown: Oh, second level slot.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: And I'm gonna place the sensor...
Seeker: We don't really know anything about the layout of the buildings though, do we?
DM: I mean, all you could see from a distance was it looked like, you know,
DM: buildings around a central courtyard, and then there's like a, a bell tower in the central courtyard.
Seeker: I might learn nothing by looking
Unknown: from the center of the courtyard.
Seeker: We could gamble about a vantage point inside one of the buildings, but again-
Kenzo: I would just do the central courtyard
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: But I don't know, that might be wrong.
Wellby: With a, with a view of the bell tower?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, the-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: Maybe in the bell tower
Kenzo: ... yeah, can you in the bell tower looking down around the, yeah
Seeker: Does the bell tower have like an open structure?
DM: So it's like, it's like solid base, and then there's a, a place where the bell is that's open.
DM: So, and then-
Kenzo: Maybe up there, so you can see all the way down around
DM: ... and then going up above the top, there's some s- some like crystal structure that extends up above the bell platform
Unknown: A crystal structure?
DM: You can't see any details. It's just like something.
Unknown: I, I think actually I'm gonna put it
Unknown: up high-
Kenzo: I like that
Unknown: ... near the bell tower-
Seeker: ... so I can look, I can inspect the crystal structure and also see down into the courtyard and through any windows.
Kenzo: That, that's great.
DM: All right.
Kenzo: Love that.
DM: So
DM: you see, um, this looks like, so
Unknown: there's the bell tower.
DM: The, the, the bell is intact.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, but this, the structure that stands on top of it looks like it once was like a,
DM: like a giant sort of crystalline light that's now broken and cracked.
DM: Like you can see mirrors, like it was clearly...
Unknown: It's like a lighthouse almost.
Unknown: Weird.
DM: But it would've sh- shown somehow, probably magic, but it's like clearly sort of also constructed, right?
DM: It's not just a crystal that glows magically, right?
DM: It's like-
Unknown: A mechanism
DM: ... a mechanism, but the mechanism is destroyed or cracked.
DM: Um, the bell is intact, and then looking down, the courtyard is in pretty good shape, right?
DM: Like it's paved, um,
DM: and-
Unknown: This is definitely where you steer the island from
DM: ... and it's [laughs], and there's eight, so there's eight temples that surround the courtyard, each one with a separate statue of the,
DM: of the eight gods of Mos Numena.
DM: No
DM: sign of anything there, just the moonlight shining over the stones.
Unknown: No lights?
DM: No lights,
DM: no torches, no fires, no movement, no weird creepy shadows, no
DM: dragons.
Seeker: Try sound for a minute just to see.
DM: You hear the sort of
DM: murmur of the wind.
Seeker: All's qui- all's quiet here.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Seeker: It seems we should approach quietly.
Kenzo: Do we, um...
Seeker: Oh, signs of just like recent foot traffic, like any wear on the stones or like leaves piled and...
Unknown: Make a investigation check
Wellby: So [die rolling] 18.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, three.
DM: Is it your perspective is a little bit high to see any, like, careful detail because the...
DM: I mean, the bell tower goes up fairly tall, right?
Wellby: Mm. Oh, yeah. I'm high up.
DM: And you're up above the bell tower, so it's hard to make out any obvious details.
DM: But it definitely doesn't seem to be destroyed in the same way that, like, the town, the port town was destroyed.
DM: Like, there's not... The, the temples are all intact.
Wellby: Mm.
Unknown: Like, their roofs, they're, like, not...
DM: And there's no... There's definitely not signs of, you know, a large group of something living here, right?
Unknown: Like, there's no-
Wellby: No trash. There's no-
DM: There's no trash. There's no...
DM: Yeah, there's no, like, scraps of food.
DM: There's no, like, clothes hanging out to dry.
DM: There's no, like, signs of substantial inhabitation.
DM: But if, like, one dragonet is walking around, like, they wouldn't really leave enough right behind for you to notice-
Wellby: Mm
DM: ... from this high up.
Wellby: [sighs] Hmm.
Seeker: Well, that's what we get from clear voice, I guess.
Unknown: [sighs] I mean...
Unknown: I also want to create.
Delwath: I, I, I still wonder if it's worth sending a message
Unknown: rather than just walking in the front door.
Kenzo: And it can, uh, send a message back.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, like, "We come in peace to seek an audience with you," kind of thing?
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: That kind of thing.
Delwath: I'll do that. I'll send the links with a message to this eldest creature.
Wellby: Okay.
Delwath: Just saying basically, we are
Unknown: travelers
Unknown: to this island
Unknown: seeking a piece
Unknown: of Rai's hand.
Unknown: We
Unknown: seek your-
Kenzo: Guidance
Unknown: ... guidance.
Kenzo: Counsel.
Unknown: And counsel.
Wellby: Piece of Rai's hand.
DM: Piece of Rai's hand.
Wellby: In, in the possession of the dragon.
Delwath: Seeking the piece of Rai's hand in the possession of...
Unknown: What was the guy's name? Uh, Ron-
Wellby: Ra- Ra'ghemdros.
Unknown: Ra'ghemdros.
Wellby: Gotta say something about our motivation.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
Wellby: In order to further
Wellby: Rai's...
Unknown: In order to further-
Wellby: To fulfill Rai's mission
Unknown: ... in order to, in order to
Unknown: preserve, continue...
Unknown: In order to continue Rai's
Unknown: mission.
Wellby: Nice.
Kenzo: Uh, or, uh-
Wellby: To hold back the-
Kenzo: Yeah. Do we want to specifically say-
Unknown: I wasn't gonna mention Hkar
Kenzo: ... we don't, we don't, we don't... We shouldn't have mentioned his name.
Kenzo: But, um,
Kenzo: um, uh, we can say something like, uh, um, you know, it's, like, maintaining the...
Unknown: I think continue, or, like,
Delwath: continue Rai's mission is pretty...
Delwath: If, if it's somebody who knows what Rai was doing,
Unknown: they know what Rai was doing.
Kenzo: Yeah, fair.
Delwath: Um, and then we,
Delwath: uh, we, we seek an audience and, and wish to know
Delwath: if it is safe and advisable to approach.
Kenzo: Oh, we could also ask the augury thing and be like, "Hey, is it okay?
Kenzo: It's... Should we just like walk up?"
Unknown: Sure.
Kenzo: I mean, I think we should do this too.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Let's just [clicks tongue] do this first.
Unknown: So the link goes off.
DM: Send a message.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Yeah. So it'll take it, like...
DM: I forget how fast it goes.
DM: Like-
Delwath: Uh, it can go really pretty fast.
Unknown: It, if it's on- If it's within...
Delwath: If it's a short distance, it goes faster.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Um, so it's probably-
Kenzo: Should we short rest anyways while we wait?
Delwath: I mean, that I was just thinking maybe we should short rest while we're waiting.
Kenzo: That'd be great. That'll get all my ki back.
DM: Okay.
DM: Send it off. Short rest.
Unknown: Yes. No response comes.
Wellby: Is there, like, a delivery receipt though?
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Do you know that it got there?
Unknown: Um...
DM: You can... I think you can tell it to, like, wait for a certain amount of time for a response.
Delwath: Yeah. Hold on. Let me double check. Well, to...
Delwath: Let's see. Uh, the message is a written or spoken message of up to 1,000 words.
Delwath: It'll travel to the named person or described person, deliver the message, wait for a time you designate for a response, and then travel back to you.
Unknown: Uh...
Kenzo: Does it just, like, say all this out loud?
DM: You can either write it down or it says it all out loud, yes.
Unknown: Um-
Kenzo: Why not say it out loud if it's being held captive?
Delwath: I mean, it's, it's a...
Unknown: Let me just... Let's see. We can choose to speak.
Kenzo: We just, like, tell the [laughs] thing to lose all of our supplies.
Unknown: 50 miles per hour. [laughs]
Wellby: I'm imagining Kenza saying that as the link vanishes around the bend in the trail.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: So it's going f- it can go 50 miles an hour.
DM: So it goes... Yeah, in, like, 10 minutes.
Wellby: Wow.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: But wait. But wait.
DM: How long do you want it to wait?
Delwath: I want it to wait an hou- I mean, 50 mi- it, we're only two miles by the most direct route.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: 50 miles an hour at two miles is 15 minutes.
Kenzo: So we just, we're, we just alert- we just alerted the, the demonic thing that's holding Dimitar.
DM: So it's gonna wait an hour.
Delwath: But it's gonna wait an hour for a response.
DM: No response.
Delwath: But we could write it down and we could give it a written message.
DM: You could.
Kenzo: That's what I was saying 'cause, like, it's, it's...
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... if Dimitar's being held captive, we don't want to, like, announce to his captor like, "Hey, we're the s-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, but it's a written, it's a written message. I mean, obviously it'll still show up with a written message, but it's not gonna give it to someone.
Wellby: What if Dimitar's alert?
Seeker: It's the middle of the night, though.
Kenzo: Does it only give the message to the recipient?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: It only gives the message to the recipient. It's, it's, uh-
Kenzo: Oh, if, if it's spoken, will it only be spoken to the recipient?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: It's not, like, said out loud to everybody.
Unknown: Well, I don't know. If it-
Unknown: Anybody could hear it, but it won't...
DM: If it can't find the recipient, it won't speak it to whoever happens to be-
Kenzo: But the written message also would only be given to the, uh-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... would only be given to the recipient.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right.
DM: It, it is-
Kenzo: And do we know that it was delivered?
DM: It's 9:00 at night.
Wellby: It's night time.
Kenzo: Do we know that it was delivered?
Delwath: Do... I mean, I don't think there's anythi- I mean, there's nothing in what you wrote.
Unknown: I've never imagined this, like,
Unknown: knowing-
Kenzo: Is there a read receipt?
Delwath: I don't... Is there? I-
DM: Just left on sent
Delwath: I feel like I would know if the
DM: You would know if it didn't find the person.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: If it finds the person and doesn't get...
DM: Like, there's nothing to...
DM: Like, it could drop off a message, wait for an hour, the person could just ignore the dro- me-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... the written message, and it would come back, and you know it found the person.
DM: You, it doesn't have the ability to, like, communicate
Unknown: But so the lynx comes back, right?
DM: The lynx comes back.
Unknown: After an hour.
DM: After an hour.
Unknown: And?
DM: No response.
Delwath: But did it fi- I mean, it didn't, like, wander around for the hour looking for the person.
DM: Yeah, yeah. No.
Unknown: It found the person.
DM: It definitely found the person.
Kenzo: Wait, and so does... If it found...
Kenzo: Do you get information from the lynx about how, where it went and, like, how it got there?
DM: No, no.
Delwath: I can't really communicate with the ly- Like, it's not...
Delwath: The lynx is like a ghostly spirit.
Unknown: It's not like an actual-
DM: No, it's not something you talk to. It just
Unknown: It doesn't really have any intelligence.
DM: I see.
Unknown: Like
DM: It's not a familiar. It's just like a spirit messenger.
DM: So you finish your short rest uneventfully.
Unknown: Okay. Well, I'm gonna take a short rest. That's useful.
Kenzo: So that's ominous.
Delwath: That is. We also, by the way, anybody who had the bonus hit points
Unknown: Yeah, delete those bonus hit points.
Unknown: Oh, oh, oh, nope, don't delete them.
Delwath: I cast it again before the short rest.
DM: There you go.
DM: Don't tempt me.
Delwath: I mean, I used my, um, I used my once a day get back two slots.
Delwath: So I have one slot left. Is there anything else I want to cast?
DM: Uh
Unknown: Can I try and scry Dimitar?
DM: You can tr- You, you...
DM: There's nothing stopping you from trying to scry on literally anybody.
Kenzo: You should totally try to scry Dimitar.
Unknown: Yeah, fine. I'm gonna try and scry.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: 'Cause now, yeah, you got one more slot.
Delwath: 'Cause I have one more slot I can burn, but if we're short resting
DM: What are the, what are the scrying
Delwath: Uh, plus five for secondhand,
Unknown: and that's it.
DM: Okay.
DM: You have
Seeker: a giant crystalline magic light source on top of your bell tower, on top of your monastery, on top of your mountain, on top of your island.
Kenzo: It's like-
Unknown: What's your DC?
DM: Uh, 19, I believe.
Kenzo: But it's when you're like a walking island and you want to, like, let people know you're walking around.
Unknown: It's to prevent collisions more than anything.
Kenzo: Yeah, with other walking islands.
Kenzo: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: You see
Kenzo: Oh
DM: ... a very, um, elderly,
DM: um, dragonet.
Unknown: Same kind of creature as before.
DM: Their skin is almost a light gray.
DM: It seems like all color has faded from their skin.
DM: There's, like, a few faint little traces of purple that you can see.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: And they're currently walking slowly around the inside of a temple.
DM: You can't tell which one it is from the inside, and seem to be in the process of rigging some kind of trap to drop from the ceiling on whoever enters the temple.
Delwath: [laughs] Um, I can't tell which temple it was?
DM: Uh
Delwath: There's no iconography inside the temple?
DM: Oh, I guess you have darkvision, right?
DM: So
Delwath: Yeah, darkvision to 120 feet.
DM: Right. Um, uh, this is
Unknown: No, I have eyes of the-
DM: Right, so you can see
Delwath: I can see in all darkness of any sort.
DM: So it's pitch, it's pitch black inside the temple.
DM: Um,
DM: uh,
DM: I guess there's, like, a faint little bit of moonlight through some windows.
Unknown: Um, you can see the, uh,
DM: um...
DM: Yeah, it's, it's the, the statue that you recognize would be The Sibyl,
DM: and it seems to be... But it seems like the inside of the temple has been kind of, like, a lot of the stones have been sort of shifted around, like clearly somebody's lived inside
DM: here.
Kenzo: So this is like, uh, Home Alone Dimitar or edition.
Seeker: For sure. Like, he detected the clairvoyance and was like, "All right, I know what's going on."
Delwath: Well, or the message, but
Unknown: maybe he just refused to read it.
Unknown: I can't tell if he read it or not.
DM: He just doesn't trust it.
Kenzo: Yeah, it's... He seems like he totally read it.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: I'll watch him for a few minutes.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: What kind of trap is he setting up?
DM: Um, there's like a giant stone that he's, like, kind of pulling on to a series of pulleys to lift
DM: up above.
Kenzo: Is there, like, a sandwich at the bottom or something in there?
Kenzo: [laughs]
Seeker: Some tiny but delicious looking snack.
DM: It's a little piece of fruit sitting on, in the door entrance here.
Kenzo: Well, he knows that he lives in Elsweyr, so.
Delwath: Yeah. What, like, I'm gonna study the trap for a little bit.
Unknown: What's the trigger mechanism?
Unknown: Is it obvious?
DM: Um, he hasn't gotten to the trigger mechanism yet.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: Right now he seems to be just struggling with some pulleys and rope to, like, lift...
DM: Like, it looks like a pretty substantial-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... block of stone,
DM: presumably set up to fall on your heads when you enter the inside.
Kenzo: And there's only one door in here?
Unknown: There's only one door into the temple, just the main door.
Unknown: Because you don't live to be as grand as you are-
Unknown: By trusting people
DM: ... by trusting everyone.
Kenzo: All right.
Unknown: Um
Kenzo: Well, that's good though. He's not cap- he's not being held captive, you know?
Unknown: He's not being held captive.
Kenzo: Yeah, so.
Unknown: That is true.
Kenzo: This is, this was actually good. Thought we were gonna have to do some weird battle with demonic things, but
Unknown: I did too.
Unknown: Okay. So
Delwath: yeah, he's setting up a trap.
Unknown: He doesn't trust us.
Kenzo: It's fine. I wouldn't trust us either.
Kenzo: I barely trust you guys. [laughs]
Unknown: So do you continue, continue walking?
Kenzo: Trust is strong here. [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, I think we-
Kenzo: Let's just go in. Let's go talk to him.
Delwath: I mean, yeah, we should avoid the trap.
Kenzo: Let's avoid the trap, but also, I mean, I'm, I've got a staff with four pieces of the jade on it.
Kenzo: I mean-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... he'll, he'll talk to us.
Wellby: And is there an obvious way to disarm the trap?
Delwath: Well, I didn't... I guess scrying doesn't last long enough to see the mechanism.
Kenzo: It only lasts 10, it only lasts 10 minutes.
DM: You just saw him, like
Delwath: And I wanted to short rest, so I didn't want to scry again.
DM: Struggling to pull the giant block of stone up, but you didn't see the mechanism that he was trying to set.
Delwath: So he's had an hour to still build it since we
DM: Yeah, this is right at the beginning.
DM: It's sort of been,
DM: this would've been shortly after-
Unknown: As soon as I sent...
Delwath: No, not even. As soon as I sent the lynx, we would've s- I would've cast scry pretty much.
Delwath: Or, like, it's not... 'Cause the hour, actually the hour, I would've probably seen...
Delwath: Okay, so the point was to short rest during the hour the lynx was gone.
DM: Okay, well this hap- this is all happening after the links came.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So maybe you didn't see it.
Unknown: Well, no, the links would have-
DM: Oh, the links would've been there faster
Unknown: ... the links got there in two minutes.
Unknown: It was the 50 mile an hour wind.
DM: Right, so you actually see the links waiting there.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And your scribe is just standing there
Unknown: With the, like message glowing in its jaw or something.
DM: And it seems to be ignoring it completely.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Oh, but, but he was, but he read the message.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, there's no way to tell.
Delwath: I can't tell if he read the message.
Delwath: The message isn't... it's not, I never envisioned it as like a piece of paper.
DM: It's not just a piece... it's not a piece of paper, right?
DM: It's like the, the spirit shows up and you either,
DM: it either starts speaking in Delwath's voice or like glowing letters appear in front of the person, right?
DM: And they can
Unknown: either speak or write a response.
DM: The only reason for the written is in cases where you might need to communicate without
DM: alerting-
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: Right. Right, so you could send a written message to like a prisoner and it wouldn't alert the guards or something.
DM: But it's all magic. It's not like...
DM: it's, it doesn't carry like a scroll in its jaw that it drops in front of you.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: Right? It's just-
Kenzo: Let's go up to the temple.
Unknown: Well, yeah, let's do it.
Kenzo: Have a chat with this dude.
Unknown: Let's do it.
DM: So you keep walking.
DM: After another, like half an hour of walking, you, you come to the point where the road curves and it seems to spiral, to join, um, like a circular road.
DM: And just where it joins this road that's circling up to the top of the mountain, um, you see, uh, again, on the edge of the path,
DM: a sort of a slight clearing where there's two unusually tall trees.
DM: And almost like growing between the trees there's this sort of curving piece of, uh, sort of pale gray stone, but it looks like...
DM: this actually sort of grows into the trees.
DM: And written on the stone are hundreds of names of elves written in Elvish.
DM: But the s- the, the scripts almost seem to like drift slowly through the stone between the two trees.
Kenzo: You recognize any of the names?
DM: Uh, no.
Unknown: I'm gonna touch it.
Kenzo: Get any vibe from it?
DM: Um,
DM: you,
DM: uh-
Delwath: I'm gonna add my name if I can.
Kenzo: What?
Kenzo: This is like some sacred thing for like dead elves, and you're just like-
Unknown: This is a memorial to the elves that fell so many years ago.
Kenzo: Dead, yeah. Like you tag it.
Unknown: Well-
Kenzo: Ugh
Delwath: ... no, no, no. I think it's a...
Unknown: I mean, it depends on what the vibe I get is.
DM: Oh.
Delwath: But if it's about elves who are coming here in a ritual context.
Delwath: If it's not a memorial, if it's elves leaving their own like I'm here as a-
DM: So, so when you-
Delwath: Like, I can't tell if your vibe is Vietnam War memorial wall or like
Unknown: leave your name.
DM: So here's what happens when you touch it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So when you touch it, um, one of these like names kind of drifts towards your hand and you suddenly have a memor- A, you suddenly see a vision or a memory-
Kenzo: Mm
DM: ... of, um, an elf standing in a rank of hundreds of elves, um,
DM: on a battlements watching a
DM: fleet of ships sailing
DM: on a sea. You don't recognize any of this.
DM: Um, and as they're, um, drawing their, like arrows, suddenly they all draw their arrows and suddenly like all of the arrows burst into flames immediately
DM: as they're released from the bows, and this rain of fire flies down on the ships.
DM: And then something flies up from one of the ships, like a,
DM: not a dragon, like some sort of twisted beast like the Nazgul creatures in The Lord of the Rings, right?
DM: And dives down and grabs this elf and like rips him-
Unknown: That, that sounds like... never mind. I'm not, I'm not adding anything.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: My first impression was this is like a-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... like as a pilgrimage to Posham.
DM: Yeah. Then you, you see echoes of like memories going back of this elf, of like the sort of history of-
Kenzo: This is cool though
DM: ... this elf.
Kenzo: Like learn more about the... this is, this is some histor-
DM: Yeah, no, I'm kind of-
Kenzo: This, this is some historical like...
Kenzo: yeah, learn, learn, this is like some like, you know, Netflix documentary of like, uh, you know-
DM: The-
Kenzo: ... True Crimes
DM: ... it, it seems like-
Kenzo: Downfall Elf
DM: ... it seems like the, so the, the sort of magic of it is when you put your hand there, some names sort of drift towards you, right?
DM: Like the ones that maybe are
DM: the, the closest to you and you,
DM: you, you see back in this person's life and you see that they were originally,
DM: uh, they first joined the army as a quarter master, and you see them cooking, right?
DM: You see like they were...
DM: you, you get a sort of reflection or echo of some of the
DM: things they left behind and the people that they, other elves and humans that they could afford.
Delwath: Any way of telling where they were born, Agrilak?
Unknown: Or-
DM: No.
Kenzo: But this is-
DM: Long ago and far away.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: But y- the sense, like the feeling you get is like this,
DM: your in- your intuition is that all of these are names of elves who died.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: And the one that's drawn to you, the one that's like drawn to your hand when you touch it, is the one that's like-
Delwath: I'm gonna gesture for Kenzo to come over and see.
DM: Sure.
Unknown: We should see what happens.
DM: Hmm. Nothing.
Unknown: Racist.
Wellby: [laughs] Like Delwath knew that that would be the case.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I mean, you-
Unknown: Touch the point
DM: ... it's not nothing. I, uh, um, like you, you don't see the like flashes of memory, but you definitely feel the sort of vibe.
DM: Like you get more of a th- there's no specific elf that kind of is drawn to Kenzo.
DM: Um,
DM: but you get this sort of vibe, right?
DM: You get the sort of general sense of, you know, all of these are people who died in battle.
DM: Like you get this echo of like the lives of all of these people and sort of just a vague sense of-
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: ... you know.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo goes to, uh, talk to the tree.
Kenzo: 'Cause you know, there are two trees and then the-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... yeah.
DM: Um, what do you say to it?
Kenzo: Well, first, um, fir- you know, again, really, really critical when talking to trees.
Kenzo: Now step number one is always consent.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: So, so Kenzo gets close to the tree and, um, as it, as he, as he approaches, holding his, uh, you know, staff made out of elven, you know, whatever-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... um, uh, you know, kind of asks for permission to, to touch it and to get close.
DM: You,
DM: you get this sense of something kind of
DM: being drawn out from a deep sleep, but also yes, and also
DM: a weird sense of recognition.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: Like when you were in Ormos-
Kenzo: Mm-hmm
DM: ... and there was that giant tree in the middle of the city that you had to commune with for a while.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: It's like the same.
Kenzo: Cool.
Kenzo: Um, yeah, I'll, uh, get close to the tree.
Kenzo: I will, uh, take my staff and, um, you know, nestle it into-
DM: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... you know, part of the root structure, and then, you know, put, put my hand on it, and I will introduce myself.
DM: The tree kind of very slowly
DM: begins to talk.
DM: It hasn't in
DM: too long.
Kenzo: Oh, fuck, it's talking. All right.
Unknown: I mean, you're using Speak with Plants, right?
DM: Of course it's talking.
Kenzo: Cool. Um,
Kenzo: how long have you slumbered?
DM: There have been
DM: no pilgrims
DM: for
DM: 700 years.
Kenzo: 700 years ago was when-
DM: Mm
Kenzo: ... Drankor fell.
Kenzo: Uh.
Delwath: Wow, I wonder how precisely dating can we trust the trees?
DM: I wouldn't trust it to the year.
DM: I would trust it to the century.
Delwath: So, like, we can't determine if pilgrims stopped when Apollyon-
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: The pilgrims, humans, elves,
Kenzo: others?
DM: All of those of Drankor
DM: were welcome here.
Kenzo: All right, and really quick meta game, so, uh,
Kenzo: Drankor,
Kenzo: elves were down with Drankor, or certain elves were.
DM: Ear- So the, like, grand history of Drankor, early on it was, like, this
DM: very sort of open city where humans and elves and these Paranar, which are, like, the weird half elves, and anybody else, like, was super welcome.
DM: And then there was a civil war between-
Unknown: Between
DM: ... a civil war among Drankorian emperors between, like, Omnis Pura, who became the cleansed, and the other people.
DM: And Omnis Pura won, and then it got shifted pretty dark.
DM: And then 200 years after that, Apollyon came to power and everything fell apart.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: So there was this... I mean, this you all learned from Orestes, right, the elf.
DM: Like, there was-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... this
DM: early period before the civil war when, like, elves were welcome in Drankor, like everybody, like there were all sorts of species in Drankor, right?
DM: Like dwarves and stoneborn and anybody,
DM: um...
DM: But then it became increasingly human as the-
Kenzo: Mm-hmm
DM: ... after Omnis Pura won the civil war.
Seeker: And so 700 years ago would have been before the civil war.
DM: No, after.
DM: No, that would have been after the civil war.
Unknown: 'Cause-
Kenzo: Civil war was like 900 years ago.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Oh, okay.
Delwath: The Drankor fell around 1,000.
DM: I mean, again, don't trust it to the year, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So sometime between when the civil war
DM: ended and when Drankor fell is, like, the basic idea of-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... when the last one fell.
Delwath: But it, it could have been when Drankor-
Unknown: Right after the civil war could have been when Drankor fell, right.
Unknown: Could have been when Drankor fell.
Kenzo: Huh.
Seeker: But so what, well, what was the role of the elves in all this?
Delwath: Well, the Paranar were part, were very much part of Drankorian-
DM: Yeah, like a lot of the early Drankorian emperors were Paranar.
Delwath: So I mean, the elves here could have been Paranar, right?
Unknown: Like, it's not...
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: And so the, the battle being commemorated?
DM: The one Delwath saw a vision of?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Could have been the Downfall War.
Unknown: So I, I...
Kenzo: So really long time ago.
Delwath: Yeah. Or it could have been some battle that Drankor fought against, I mean, who knows, right?
Kenzo: Right.
Kenzo: So I, I asked the, I asked the tree, um,
Unknown: the names here
Kenzo: written on, on the, uh...
Unknown: Is it a walkway or what's the...
Unknown: Is it-
DM: Um, it-
Unknown: ... like the stone structure
DM: ... so what it looks like is, like, as if branches of the two trees grew, but they were not wood, they were stone until they met.
Unknown: But they, it doesn't block the path?
DM: No, it's on the side of the path.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: It's along the side of the path.
Unknown: Oh, wait, the trees are-
DM: There's two trees on the side of the...
DM: The road goes like this. The trees are here.
Unknown: Ah, got it.
Unknown: And then there's these branches that go between them.
Delwath: I wasn't envisioning... Oh, so the trees aren't on either side.
Unknown: They're both-
DM: The trees aren't on either side.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: They're next to each other.
Unknown: I missed that.
DM: The branches grow-
Unknown: Got it. I thought they were-
DM: ... and where they touch, they kind of turn to this stone-like substance.
Unknown: Yeah, got it, yeah.
Kenzo: The, the names, the names of, uh, the elves here, who are they?
DM: They're who we re- remember, who left too soon.
Kenzo: Why these elves?
DM: They are who we remember.
Kenzo: You said there haven't been pilgrims for centuries.
Kenzo: Why?
DM: We don't know.
Kenzo: There is a-
DM: Hmm
Kenzo: ...
Kenzo: a b- uh,
Kenzo: uh, near here, I saw a pool
Kenzo: with the reflection of Tortured souls.
Kenzo: Do you know what that is?
DM: A pool?
Kenzo: A reflection.
DM: Not all the pools.
DM: Not all the memory pools could be saved.
Kenzo: What are the memory pools?
DM: They're how we remember
DM: the ones who passed on.
DM: All the ones who passed on.
Kenzo: Are the memories stored in the pool?
DM: The tree is sort of confused, like, "What are you talking about?"
DM: Like-
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: ... it's all part of the same thing.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: So.
Seeker: I wonder if that's why the rivers don't make it to the sea.
Delwath: 'Cause they're actually memories and you don't wanna lose them?
Seeker: Or if the rivers are just being diverted for this purpose.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I, I think they're more magical than that, right?
Kenzo: Like...
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: [sighs] anything else from the tree?
Kenzo: Is the island...
Kenzo: Are you at peace here?
DM: Seems to like think for a moment.
Unknown: We are at peace,
DM: but beyond
DM: us,
DM: who can say?
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: To the west.
DM: That is beyond us.
Kenzo: The dragon?
DM: Beyond us.
Seeker: I wonder if this is, this is a solitary tree or a network of trees.
Unknown: I mean, it's probably the whole... Yeah, the, the, the forest.
DM: Yeah, it's, I mean, it's clearly the, like it's the whole forest.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's all one thing.
Unknown: Awesome.
Kenzo: The elder dragon. The elder dragonet.
DM: Doesn't say anything.
Kenzo: Friend?
Unknown: I don't, we don't know you yet.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: Delwath seems fairly, I mean-
Kenzo: You, you don't know me.
Kenzo: Uh, you know, the tr- the, the, um,
Kenzo: the, uh, staff,
Kenzo: jade,
Kenzo: the s-
Kenzo: the story, uh, um...
Kenzo: You don't know me,
Kenzo: but I hope you can sense the stories and the history
Kenzo: and the stories that are told from
Kenzo: my staff.
Kenzo: They tell
Kenzo: the story of me in a way.
DM: You have traveled many places.
Kenzo: I have.
Kenzo: And that's all it says.
Kenzo: Um-
Unknown: Ah. All right. Oh, oh, wait.
Seeker: Did it say you have traveled or I have traveled?
DM: To Kenzo. You have traveled.
Unknown: Might be interesting to ask the tree
Seeker: if it has any sense of the island having moved.
Kenzo: Oh.
Seeker: One way to ask it is if the climate conditions have changed radically [laughs] which we think would happen-
Kenzo: Oh
Seeker: ... if it moved 1,000 miles or whatever.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: That's what's happened.
Kenzo: Ask it that. H- have you ever moved?
Kenzo: Have you-
Unknown: Or have-
Kenzo: Have you ever traveled? 'Cause it, it said, what'd it say?
Kenzo: It said, uh, you, you've traveled.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Ask it if it's ever traveled.
DM: We came later.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: What?
Kenzo: When did you come?
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Ask if there's anyone left on the island who came when the island moved.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: We came
DM: when a refuge
DM: became a memorial.
Kenzo: Oh.
Delwath: Ah, Delwath will ask, there are many elves...
Kenzo: You, you can't talk to the tree.
Delwath: Well, I'm just gonna talk to the-
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: there are ma- Delwath seems sort of moved by all this.
Delwath: There are many elves who have died with no one to remember them.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: Hmm.
Delwath: Can, can you accept more memories?
DM: We have not.
DM: We have been cut off for a long, long time.
DM: Once, yes.
Kenzo: Okay, so, so this is the last thing.
Kenzo: Um, this is less, like, communicated in words, but more like,
Kenzo: um,
Kenzo: I, I seek or, or, um,
Kenzo: your memorial, your mem- uh, your memorial is beautiful.
Unknown: It tells the stories
Kenzo: of those you seek to remember.
Kenzo: I also...
Kenzo: And, and you do it through these, through the names of the, those who- ...
Kenzo: uh, y- are to be remembered,
Kenzo: I also tell the stories of those I want to remember,
Kenzo: um, and can be remembered.
Kenzo: Uh, and I, I basically tell it that I want to also remember it, and I'm saying it as, like, the...
Kenzo: Like, and I- I'm asking for it to share back to me a memory or an image that I can put into the staff.
DM: You... Yeah, I guess what you're going for.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, you see, you see an image of
DM: what must be long ago, the moon still shining, um,
DM: and people walking on the road.
DM: A- you know, everybody's, you know, carrying different things.
DM: Like, there's a couple elves, there's humans.
DM: Um,
DM: there's, like, one stoneborn.
DM: Like, it's not... It's a mixed species flock, right?
DM: Like, there's this just people traveling, and, and you do get the feel it, like you have a sort of vibe, right?
DM: It's not a clear image. It's more of a vibe.
DM: Yeah. It is mostly humans and elves, but...
DM: And everybody is remembered in different ways, right?
DM: The, the
DM: humans have their gods, the elves have their gods.
DM: But everywhere through the forest, everybody is remembered.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: And then, and you get the vibe of, like, the forest.
DM: Y- you know, it's vibrant, right?
DM: It's like, you know, the s- the moon is shining, but the leaves are sort of rustling.
DM: The f- flowers are blooming.
DM: There's... And it seems it's much more alive than it seems now.
DM: Like, the trees are fine, right, but there's-
Kenzo: Hmm
DM: ... just less.
DM: Th- everything's duller-
Kenzo: Mm-hmm
DM: ... than it once was, and
DM: there's almost this echo of, like, a sense of loss.
DM: Like, something was
DM: cut off.
DM: Something was...
DM: The, the, the forest, the trees, all speaking as the collective sense, were
DM: isolated somehow.
Kenzo: And they don't know how.
DM: They don't know how.
Kenzo: Yeah. All right.
Kenzo: Yeah, 'cause I was gonna carve, like, a really cool, like,
Kenzo: forest thing, like, around the,
Kenzo: with the path and people walking through it.
DM: You're growing a bit elvish.
Kenzo: What's that?
Delwath: You're growing a bit elvish, Kenzo.
Kenzo: What you talking about? I'm just...
Kenzo: I just, I just honor, um, really cool stories.
Unknown: From all species.
Kenzo: From all species, 'cause all species matter, Delwath.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: All species matter.
Kenzo: All species matter. [laughs] Ah.
DM: I mean, the vibe of the forest is very much not, like, only elves matter, right?
DM: It's like-
Kenzo: Oh, interesting. Wow, mixed species must make you feel a little weird, huh, being in this, like, place where-
Unknown: Everybody matters. That's what we always say
DM: This memorial is an elven memorial, but it doesn't mean that there are no other memorials elsewhere.
Kenzo: Cool. Uh, Kenzo, you know, gratefully thanks the tree.
Wellby: Hmm. Do you ask if there are any other trees from before the island was here?
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. I ask it that.
DM: Trees from b- No, the...
DM: They don't really understand the question.
DM: There's not... They don't... There's not many trees.
DM: There's just one.
Kenzo: Oh, wait, it's, it's, it, it-
Wellby: No, so the whole of the forest has not traveled.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: It's like one-
DM: It's like one
Wellby: ... kind of thing.
Kenzo: But they... I, I also, when I asked it if it had, if it had traveled,
Kenzo: it said that...
Kenzo: So it's, but it said, yeah, that said-
DM: We came when-
Kenzo: After the memorial
Unknown: ... a refuge turned to a memorial.
Kenzo: Right. So, so they were here, they were here before the...
Kenzo: after the island moved.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Seeker: And it was a refuge. For whom?
Delwath: It was a refuge for the people fleeing Hkar.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: And then it became a memorial.
Delwath: And then it became a memorial of all the losses in the Downfall.
Unknown: I wonder if it was part of Hkar.
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, we'll find out when we play the Downfall-
DM: Oh, huh
Kenzo: ... campaign.
Delwath: Maybe it's part of Hkar and it has that same magic of-
Kenzo: Our, our, our characters from the Downfall campaign have to create the island, so-
Unknown: Wait, what's, what's the-
Kenzo: ... there's a whole-
Unknown: Finish that thought
Delwath: Well, there's a, there's a non-canonical idea, what Tim was saying earlier, that maybe Hkar has some special magic about it that makes divine...
Delwath: It makes it easier to birth new gods.
Unknown: Ah.
Delwath: But that's why Apollyon came here, is because he wants to become a god.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: So how is he gonna birth himself as a new god?
Delwath: Well, there's a magic to Hkar.
Seeker: How would we find out if this was actually part of Hkar?
Delwath: Well, I think the next step is to explore the various places that Tim has set on the island.
Unknown: Trust your leader.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: I mean, Dunmire Seeker has, like, various abilities.
Seeker: Shit. What do you n- [laughs] There's something that I can find out by doing something that I'm supposed to know, but I don't know that I know.
Kenzo: [laughs] If only I read my character sheet.
DM: You can do things like Kenzo does.
Kenzo: Talk to the stone.
Unknown: Oh, wait.
Seeker: I have, like, my stone sense and my tremor sense, but those are just to, like,
Seeker: find out what kinds of stone are there, not, like, talk to the stone.
Unknown: Is it-
DM: No, you can't talk to the stone.
Unknown: But what are...
Kenzo: [laughs]
Seeker: The stone sense ability just changed, so let me just-
Kenzo: I mean, we are walking on, like, weird magic stone roads and stuff, or...
Seeker: Can I... How do I
Seeker: do... What characterizes Hkar
Unknown: stone-wise?
Kenzo: Can you talk to the, or can you sense the weird clip material stone things?
DM: I mean, you can alternately replace one or both of your questions with information of a similar scope.
Kenzo: What is it?
Unknown: About, like, age.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: But, no, would that tell us anything about Hkar?
DM: Well, I don't know.
DM: You could certainly find out how old the stone is, though.
Kenzo: That would be super useful.
Seeker: I missed that part about the scope.
Seeker: Oh, I will ask about tunnels, burrows, or other significant undergroun- underground excavation You get two.
Delwath: Ask for how old it is and underground.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Okay, okay.
DM: It's only within 1,000 feet though.
Seeker: But, but we're up, we're up near the top of the mountain, right?
DM: You could wait till you're like within 1,000 feet from the top of the mountain, yeah.
Seeker: It sounds like we should wait till within, we're within 1,000 feet of the top of the mountain to do this.
Unknown: Yeah. Uh, that sounds wise.
Wellby: Aren't we within...
Delwath: I mean, we're not, but the trees were further down.
DM: Oh, I guess actually as, as, by a straight line you are probably within 1,000 feet of the top.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: 'Cause the trees are where, the trees are like partway up, so the, like all of the roads come in to like this central
DM: circular road that like spirals up-
Wellby: Right
DM: ... to the top. So.
Wellby: Fine.
Kenzo: I only ever eat Swedish Fish with you guys.
DM: Evil.
DM: Um.
Wellby: Eric's-
DM: So yeah, okay.
Unknown: Eric's like...
Delwath: There's a smarter end of the table and a stupider end
Wellby: ... Eric, I need more Ted to the table.
Unknown: All right, I'll just have, I can only have the one.
Kenzo: This is ce- this is ceremonial right now 'cause it's all of us together.
DM: Okay, so you come, so as you-
Wellby: Oh.
DM: So you're probably [laughs] if you follow the spiral-
Unknown: [laughs] I'm still not done
DM: ... if you follow the spiral up the road, you're probably still about a mile from the top, but by, if you just went straight up you're like 1,000 feet from the top.
Unknown: Just like him to do that. Okay.
DM: 'Cause the road sort of goes in a very gradual-
Unknown: All right, so now's actually a reasonable time-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... to do this tense. All right, I'm gonna.
DM: So
DM: the stone is
DM: like...
DM: Oh my God, I look at my tense roll.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, it's very old. It's like,
DM: I don't know, 3,000 years old.
Wellby: Oh, okay.
DM: Something like that.
Unknown: Would that line up historically?
Unknown: That'd be well before the Downfall Wars.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: But, but if the stone is anything less than the age when time began, then it was-
Unknown: No, humans weren't created when time began
Unknown: ... humans weren't created when time began.
DM: The, the timing is roughly when humans were created is the age of the stone.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah, that's part of the time. All right.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And there is one tunnel.
Unknown: Word.
Seeker: And crap, it's weather present.
Unknown: [laughs] It's not where.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Actually a non-trivial amount.
DM: I mean, it's not just one tunnel, right?
DM: Like it's a, there's a
DM: little bit of a tunnel complex
DM: somewhere.
Seeker: Probably underneath the monastery up there.
DM: Nope.
DM: So you continue.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: You reach the top
DM: around, I don't know, 10:00 PM.
DM: No. Yeah, probably 10:30, something like that.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I should have had four. That was too many.
Wellby: You had four?
DM: [laughs] That's just how many came out of the bag.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: It was a mistake.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, so as you come, you come out into this sort of clear area, the top, you know, 500 feet of the mountain is exposed.
DM: And you can see now clearly the structure, right?
DM: There's these eight temples arrayed, arrayed in a circle.
DM: There's the courtyard, there's the bell tower with the lighthouse like thing on top, and then on the outskirts there's like a number of administrative buildings.
DM: There's like clearly like one building that's fairly large and that would have been the like hostel where pilgrims could spend the night before they make the journey back the next day,
DM: right? If they arrive at dawn and they do their prayers or whatever.
DM: Um,
DM: there's,
DM: ah, you know, there's like clearly like living quarters for, um, you know, for it, whoever would've staffed this.
DM: There's, um,
DM: what... You haven't seen this before, but it looks like a,
DM: uh, like a,
DM: a mess hall where you can see it's, it's all open.
DM: It, like the, the living quarters in this are, are, and the hostel are like, you know, stone buildings basically intact, so you can't see into.
DM: But then there's like a large area where there's, um, I don't know, maybe 15 of these little arcane circles arrayed in a sort of nice way with
DM: stone benches sort of carved so people could like sit and congregate and eat.
DM: But it looks like space for a pretty large number of people, like 100 people could have ha- shared a meal there.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Peak pilgrimage season was heavy traffic.
DM: Yeah.
DM: No signs of anything moving.
DM: You can see the Temple of the Sibyl.
DM: It's obvious.
Unknown: Tell us about the Sibyl.
DM: So the Sibyl is the,
DM: the
DM: deity who is associated with
DM: magic
DM: and,
DM: um,
DM: knowledge, but also like song and love and beauty, and sometimes like obsession.
DM: [coughs] Um, her, but she's most known as, she's most like associated with like-
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: ... scholars and magic.
Unknown: Hmm. So are we knocking on the front door?
Wellby: There's only one entrance?
DM: There's only one entrance to the temple.
DM: E- all of the temples have like one main door facing the courtyard.
Unknown: I wanna check for traps.
Wellby: [laughs] Is it a single block of stone that's fr- Yeah, so I'll sneak over very stealthily to
Wellby: check out the operation of this. What I'm thinking is we have the immovable rod.
Wellby: Can we just put it above the door and hold the stone up and keep it from falling down?
Wellby: Would it just hit and tilt?
Seeker: It'll bound, it'll tip over, yeah
Wellby: Uh, depending on the geometry of the thing.
Kenzo: Would you like mage hand or like hold the stone in place?
Wellby: It's heavy.
DM: It's, it's too heavy, yeah.
Kenzo: So actually, is this like a formidable trap?
DM: Side door?
DM: Rear door?
Wellby: [clears throat]
Wellby: Mystica.
Delwath: I mean, we could just dimension door to the other side.
Wellby: Anyways, so-
Unknown: How many, how many people can dimension door?
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Okay. Yeah.
Wellby: Very, very stealthily look for how to disarm it.
Wellby: Willby, stealthy?
DM: Okay. Uh, make a stealth check and a, a, a investigation.
Wellby: Stealth's 25.
Wellby: Investigation is tw-
Wellby: uh, investigation is 12.
DM: Um, yeah, so you can tell there's a, what looks like, I mean, it's a very fine, very fine tripwire that runs along, and it's actually like, so
DM: the doors,
DM: um,
DM: the, the doors swing out.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And the way it's been rigged is so that in order to swing the doors open, you would have to break this little tripwire.
Unknown: Wait,
Delwath: is the stone above us or is it inside the temple?
DM: It's inside the temple.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You can't see the stone, but there's, there's a little hole that goes through one of the doors, like on the side of the temple, right?
DM: So it's like you swing it open, this tripwire breaks, some mechanism
DM: on the other side is released, and that moves a block that drops the pulley or something like that.
Unknown: But-
Wellby: So-
Delwath: ... if we just open the doors and don't walk through them, is it just gonna fall on us from above?
DM: No, it's, it is on the front of the door, so if you pull the doors open, the doors break the tripwire.
DM: It's like right, so there's two double doors.
Unknown: Right, but I'm so confused. Okay. So-
Kenzo: Is the stone gonna swing down and smashes the face or is it like just drop straight?
DM: It's probably gonna swing down and smash you in the face.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs]
Delwath: So I'll just open the door with mage hand.
Delwath: I mean, is it worth doing anything else?
Wellby: You know, it seems like he went to a lot of trouble to make the trap, like-
Unknown: You mean let's not trigger it?
Wellby: ... springing it seems rude.
Delwath: [laughs] Well, do you want to dimension door to the other side?
Wellby: Let's, um, tie another rope onto the wire and keep a constant tension, and then you can-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... open the door without tripping the wire.
Unknown: Great.
Wellby: I'll try that. I'll jump out of the way if the stone-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... falls, right?
Wellby: What's disarm traps?
Wellby: Is that a-
DM: Um,
DM: I mean-
Wellby: ... use tools?
Wellby: I don't know.
DM: Sure. I think given that you have an idea for how to work, it's pretty easy to set it off.
Wellby: 24.
DM: Yeah. Okay. So Wellby takes a bit of rope and like ties it so it keeps constant tension,
DM: and then you just open the doors.
Wellby: All right.
DM: What happens,
DM: you can see there's a giant stone block that's like angled down.
DM: It would like swing. It's the size of the doors.
DM: So if you normally open the doors, it would swing and clip you in the middle of the chest.
Wellby: Oh, I'm gonna give a good appreciative look and just gonna say, "Yes, that's some pretty nice work."
Wellby: Uh-
Unknown: Hello?
Wellby: And then let's, uh-
DM: Well, go in
Wellby: ... go in, yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: there's nothing inside.
DM: I mean, there's no movement.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: You say hello.
Kenzo: God, I really want to say Dimitar, but we wouldn't have it at all.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: You wouldn't. You s-
Delwath: I'll say, I'll say hello, Elder Dragonet in Elvish.
DM: The, the [laughs]
DM: the-
Delwath: Eldest. What, what did the rumor call him, the eldest?
DM: The, just the, just elder.
Unknown: Elder.
Wellby: Elder, yeah.
Unknown: I'll, I'll call out hello, elder.
DM: So the layout inside is like there's, you know, there's like-
Unknown: I'm also just casting detect thoughts, by the way
DM: ... there's a,
DM: um,
DM: you know, there's like p- there's like places people sit.
DM: There's like, it's like a sort of, sort of standard like temple arrangement.
DM: It's, it's circ- it's like sort of circular.
DM: There's seating in the middle.
DM: There's like an altar and a statue of The Sibyl at the far end.
Unknown: Bullshit. [laughs]
DM: And when you say in Elvish, um, the temple of The Sibyl booms out in a booming voice in Elvish, "Who dares disturb the rest
DM: of the gods?"
Unknown: Hmm. Is there any-
Wellby: That doesn't sound like-
Unknown: ... thinking-
Wellby: ... the temple of The Sibyl
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: No. Is there [laughs] it doesn't.
DM: Is there-
Unknown: It sounds like the Wizard of Oz
Unknown: ... it, it does. It sounds like a magic mouth.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Is there any thoughts within 30 feet of me?
DM: Uh, within 30 feet?
DM: No.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Can I look very, very perceptively
Wellby: around the room?
DM: You want to like walk around and search?
Delwath: Oh, I'm also gonna see invisible before we go in.
DM: Okay. [laughs]
Wellby: I'm gonna try and hear invisible.
DM: But are you... You're currently all like standing in the doorway, right?
Unknown: I'm-
Wellby: On the inside, out of the way in case the trap springs, but yeah, swinging
DM: ... yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. I'm gonna walk like, uh, how big is it and how far is it from here to the other end?
DM: Like
DM: 80 feet.
Unknown: Okay. So I'll walk towards the middle.
Delwath: I'll call out hello a few... I'll, I'll ignore, Delwath's gonna ignore the booming voice.
DM: As you start walking, the booming voice says, "Halt, or the gods will punish you."
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: I'm gonna check for traps.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Hold on. K- Kenzo, Kenzo just, just, uh...
Kenzo: So I saw a vision of this creature with Rai
Kenzo: in a d- in, when was the-
DM: In Dranikor with the Rai statues talking to the awakened soul monks.
Kenzo: Okay. And, and, and I had that vision when?
DM: You had, it was like a dream you had like long ago in Dun.
DM: It was like,
DM: you don't know what time it was, but you had it like around the time you were exploring the monastery of the-
Kenzo: Okay
Unknown: ... of the Beachmen monks and sort of Dranikor.
Kenzo: Okay. I say, I just say,
Kenzo: "Elder Dragon, I've seen you before
Kenzo: in the presence of..."
Kenzo: Do I, we, we, I know that that statue is Rai, right?
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: We know who Rai is.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I've s- I've seen you before in a vision
Kenzo: with Rai as a statue being visited by monks of my order.
Kenzo: I've seen a vision of you.
Kenzo: I have in my possession...
Kenzo: Or,
Kenzo: when I was born
Kenzo: my parents gave me
Kenzo: a piece of jade that I've carried with me my entire life.
Kenzo: I think you know what that is.
Kenzo: And my companions and I over the past
Kenzo: years...
Kenzo: A year? A year?
DM: Yeah, it's been more than a year.
DM: It's like a year and a half
Kenzo: ... have found more of these pieces which we know are important
Kenzo: as a part of Rai's quest.
Kenzo: And then Kenzo will make a little motion and then the top of his staff which has, is currently covered-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like will re- will, will warp back and reveal.
DM: There's a booming voice that says, "The gods demand proof that you are friends and allies of this great wizard before they will speak to you."
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Wellby will say, will point to the staff and say, "It, isn't that what he just did?"
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] You might be thieves.
Kenzo: I mean,
Wellby: I mean we might but-
Seeker: Should I just turn this thing off with the spell magic?
DM: Sure.
Kenzo: Turn, turn, I'm not even [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Have the little tiny voice.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: He's like he's got a teeny voice. That's fine.
Seeker: It's just Dimitar like behind it pulling strings.
Kenzo: Yeah, but it's fine. It's fine.
Kenzo: Um, uh, we, we share, we share Rai's purpose of making sure
Kenzo: W- Apollyon stays captive.
DM: Delwath is now standing in the middle.
Delwath: Could I detect where Dimitar, where this creature's thoughts are?
Wellby: Nope.
DM: I, I say that then.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: Mm.
Seeker: I put my hand to the f- to the stone floor and use tremor sense.
DM: Uh,
DM: there is something moving about 10 feet below the ground in a tunnel.
Seeker: I just look around and go like... [laughs]
DM: It's blocked by one foot of stone.
Unknown: Detect thoughts. Uh.
Kenzo: Wait, hold on. Hold on.
Wellby: I look for, uh, entrances to the tunnel.
DM: Wait, but it's kind of cool.
Wellby: Circular Island.
DM: We just need-
Wellby: Yeah, yeah. While, while we're still talking
DM: ... yeah, we just need to prove that we're friends.
Delwath: What, I'll, I'll, I'll ask what proof would you accept?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: If you're not accepting this proof, what proof would you accept?
DM: The, the gods are thinking for a moment.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Wait, can, can you see us right now?
Wellby: Like could you see the staff?
Unknown: There's four pieces. Four, four.
Kenzo: That's the-
Wellby: You see the jade.
DM: The gods can only hear.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Man, it's amazing.
Wellby: But that was a really dramatic reveal.
Unknown: It was a, it was awesome.
Unknown: The gods can hear no evil.
Unknown: [laughs] They cannot see no evil.
Unknown: Uh, what, hmm.
DM: Walk forward into our presence.
Kenzo: Walk forward.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Show me that again. [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, mighty gods. [laughs]
Wellby: I sort of subtly gesture where the spy hole is to look up to.
DM: You notice that like, okay, so in, um, there must be a tunnel that runs underneath the floor and then goes up like at the base of the statue and you can, Wellby would notice this.
DM: You can see that there's...
Unknown: A little peephole
DM: ... a little peephole like cut into the-
Unknown: That's great
DM: ... like base of the statue.
Kenzo: Yeah. So, so Kenzo, "Oh, mighty gods," [laughs] and then shows the, shows the, shows the staff.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, he has the staff out.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That would have been much more dramatic if you had waited.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: The gods do not appreciate your sense of timing.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Forgive me.
Kenzo: Forgive us, oh, mighty gods, for our poor timing,
Kenzo: and like le- and poor sense of dramatic timing.
DM: Um, you hear a tu- like, uh, behind the altar you hear like a scraping stone and the
DM: like so like somebody's moving a, like a, um, a stone tile, and then like climbing up you see this ancient, um,
DM: elderly dragonet, like again sort of grayish, the, what you saw in scrying.
DM: Um, and he's walking slowly.
DM: He's carrying like a short staff in one hand and a wand in the other that he's still kind of pointing at you.
Kenzo: Oh, shit.
DM: Um,
DM: and he says,
DM: not in a booming voice anymore, um,
DM: kind of blinking a little bit, "I would know the story of where you got those fragments."
Kenzo: You want to know the story?
DM: It seems important.
DM: You say there's... Wait, did you say that you were seeking one on the island?
Delwath: In our letter, but not since, not-
DM: Oh, okay. Not that-
Kenzo: Yes
DM: ... he doesn't say anything about that.
DM: He obviously didn't read the letter.
Kenzo: Yeah. [laughs] Um, well,
Kenzo: as I mentioned, um,
Kenzo: one I've had carried with me.
Kenzo: One was in, uh, what was the elvish forest thing?
Kenzo: Uh.
Delwath: It was in the Elderwood.
Kenzo: One was in the Elderwood.
Kenzo: One was with the merfolk,
Kenzo: and-
Unknown: Irske, in the far north.
Kenzo: And one was in Irsk, in the far north.
Kenzo: What do you know of this,
Kenzo: these pieces?
DM: Nothing.
DM: I mean, I know what they are.
Kenzo: You know about the other one that's here on this island?
DM: No.
Unknown: Really?
Kenzo: Is he a- aura sense. So it's, yeah, detecting-
Delwath: I'm detecting thoughts. What are his surface thoughts?
Unknown: He doesn't get a save.
Kenzo: Um.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Worn out.
DM: He's, like, super curious about...
DM: Like, he's...
DM: I mean, he's definitely...
DM: He's, like, thinking of Rai and, like, where did these people come from?
DM: Like, obviously they're...
DM: I mean, like, pretty much trust that Rai wouldn't let
DM: strange evil people carry around fragments of-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... his hand, but doesn't seem to know anything about the jade.
Unknown: I mean, I, I only get, like...
Unknown: Without him getting a save-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... I only get, like, basic surface thoughts.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: So not, like, deep motivations.
Kenzo: So yeah, like, aura, aura read.
Kenzo: Like, what's his, what's his deal? Is he, like, a ultra powerful...
DM: No.
Kenzo: Like that guy.
DM: He's not ultra powerful.
Kenzo: He's like a normal... What, what's his, uh, what's his-
DM: Eh, he's like, you know, he's...
DM: He spent, like, hundreds of years associated with Rai.
DM: He's not without his tricks.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: But he's definitely weaker than you.
Kenzo: Right. Right, right.
DM: He'd be, like, level seven or something.
Unknown: Okay. So it is Dimitaur.
DM: Yeah, it's Dimitaur.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: yeah. There's a- another piece.
Kenzo: In fact, we believe the final piece.
DM: Where did they come from?
Kenzo: The...
Unknown: Man, where to begin with all this?
Delwath: When did you last see Rai?
DM: 39 years ago.
Unknown: And he left to-
DM: I think that's right
Unknown: ... try to heal the,
Delwath: the land, and you did not go with him?
DM: No.
Delwath: But that was... Was that the last time?
DM: When he left.
Kenzo: Is he still alive?
DM: I mean,
DM: in some sense. I don't think he can die.
Kenzo: Where is he now?
DM: Still in
DM: Drankor, I think.
DM: I don't know.
Delwath: Wait, we don't know if only his hand shattered or if all of Rai shattered,
Unknown: do we? Do we know?
DM: No.
Unknown: We don't know.
Kenzo: When we found each of these pieces, we've received a vision,
Kenzo: and we've been able to see the moment when his hand shattered.
Kenzo: Were you there?
DM: No.
Unknown: No, that was when he was off trying to-
Kenzo: Yeah
Unknown: ... heal the-
Delwath: ... with the awakened soul monks, right?
Kenzo: Do you know about Apollyon?
DM: I know the stories.
DM: Many stories.
Delwath: But do you know Rai was holding his prison closed?
DM: Of course. What do you think?
DM: I'm not stupid.
DM: What is up with this Alf?
Kenzo: Yeah, we deal with him.
Kenzo: We manage. We just, it's...
Unknown: He means well.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Um, so you understand the gravity of our quest.
Kenzo: We're trying to find the last piece.
DM: I don't know why.
DM: I mean...
Delwath: He, Rai is no longer holding Apollyon's prison closed.
DM: Oh, well, that's pretty bad.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. That's why, that's why-
DM: So you didn't know that.
Wellby: He's getting out in, like, what, 10 days?
Unknown: 10 days.
Kenzo: 10 days. Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yes.
Wellby: So are we gonna have-
DM: Oh, shit.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Rogam's gonna be pissed.
Wellby: What's gonna be pissed?
Kenzo: Pissed about what?
Delwath: Why is Rogam's gonna be pissed?
Delwath: What do you know about Rogam- Rogam'dros?
DM: I mean,
DM: I don't think she knows about me, and I wanna keep it that way.
DM: So I only get, like, little bits and pieces of rumors.
DM: Uh,
DM: but, like, you know
DM: Chaumut and Apollyon had a big fight, right?
Kenzo: Yeah, we know about that, yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: You know Rogam'dros is Chaumut's daughter.
Unknown: What?
Kenzo: What? Did not know that.
DM: Some
DM: task she was appointed on this island.
DM: Something to guard, I think.
Unknown: Something to guard.
Unknown: Why do I think of Chaumut having sex?
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: Who's to say dragons have-
Unknown: Could, could be-
DM: ... children the normal way?
Kenzo: Immaculate conception. Immaculate conception.
Unknown: Sure. Wow.
DM: Uh.
Unknown: What, what is she guarding?
DM: I don't know.
Unknown: It's not the jade.
DM: What, no.
Unknown: Because that's a more recent arrival.
Wellby: I mean, could it be the island itself
Wellby: somehow?
Kenzo: Could it be the divine forge that Apollyon used to make the scepter of power?
Wellby: Hmm, where is that, by the way?
DM: Somewhere west.
Kenzo: Uh.
Seeker: And, and how did you...
Unknown: Somewhere west on the island?
Kenzo: Yeah, that's the western part of the island. It's all weird.
Unknown: Yeah, the, the, the scary thing.
Seeker: How did you come to stay here, Dimitaur?
Kenzo: Oh, we don't know his name yet.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: I thought, I thought we confirmed the name earlier.
DM: That was out of game.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You can ask his name in game.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Actually, yeah. What, what is your name?
DM: Dimitaur.
Kenzo: Huh.
Unknown: How did you come to stay here?
DM: Well,
DM: Rai never came back.
Kenzo: Back here?
DM: Back to where we were in Drankor keeping watch over Apollyon.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: I knew he had trained here.
DM: I thought,
DM: let's see.
Kenzo: How long have you been here now?
DM: Like...
DM: 35 years
Kenzo: Are you waiting for Rai here?
DM: Well, I didn't know so many of my people lived here.
DM: Now I'm kind of...
DM: I don't know what to do.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Seeker: What's your relationship like with, with the Dragonets?
DM: I'm pretty sure Ra'ghemdros would kill me if she knew I was here.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: So I don't really talk to them much, but some of them come find me secretly.
Seeker: Do you think you could enlist them to help us?
DM: Help you do what?
Seeker: We're trying to figure that out, but we need to get that jade.
DM: Ah,
DM: planners, I see.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: Planners, I see.
Kenzo: Does he say that with contempt or [laughs]
DM: A little bit with contempt.
Kenzo: I... We, we don't plan that much.
Kenzo: Don't worry. Um,
Kenzo: so you say-
DM: The important thing is to just not keep the plans you make.
Kenzo: Heh, we never do that.
Wellby: Yeah, we do. Yeah, yeah. Right.
Kenzo: So
Kenzo: the dragon, uh, is she, is she free?
Kenzo: We had a feeling she may also be captive.
DM: Eh.
Kenzo: Can she travel freely?
DM: You mean, like-
Kenzo: Can she leave her lair?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Is that...
DM: Where did you get this idea from?
Kenzo: Uh.
DM: I mean, do you know many dragons that don't leave their lairs?
Delwath: She hasn't seen too much
Delwath: according to the Dragonets down there.
DM: Well, she has some task.
DM: Maybe it's too important.
DM: I don't know.
Seeker: An important task underground?
DM: I'm not here to solve your problems, guys.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Well, what can we do to help you?
DM: [coughs] Wait, you want to help me?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, um,
DM: something more interesting to eat would be nice.
Kenzo: We can help you with that.
Wellby: We've got these berries. They're pretty good.
DM: Oh, well, fruit's easy.
DM: My circles make it.
Delwath: Hmm. I'll send the...
Delwath: my lynxes out to go collect some food.
Kenzo: I can make you a meal, Dimitar.
Seeker: I suppose this runic food gets a little old
Unknown: day in and day out.
DM: Yeah, it's like 12 menu choices.
Kenzo: That's...
DM: You gotta go out there. There's...
DM: The biggest thing is none of the ones up here are seafood.
Kenzo: Ah.
Seeker: Of course, you like a little seafood once in a while, but it's hard to get down there 'cause of all the other Dragonets, so...
DM: Also, you know, at my age,
DM: I'm not as agile as I once was in the air.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Hmm. Yeah.
Unknown: Of course. Of course.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hmm.
Kenzo: Uh, so just so you know,
Kenzo: this is our plan.
Kenzo: I know you're not, you know, but just curious your thoughts on it.
Kenzo: We, uh, want to get that last piece of jade.
Kenzo: Um, I think when we put those pieces together, um, you know, I mentioned I got a...
Kenzo: been getting a vision of, of Rai basically every time we find one of these pieces of jade.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: we
Kenzo: suspect at least that once we get the final piece together,
Kenzo: we're gonna get a pretty important piece of information about where Apollyon is,
Kenzo: um, storing himself,
Kenzo: and probably in Drankor someplace.
DM: Where-
Kenzo: Probably gonna have to go in.
DM: Wait, you don't know that already?
Kenzo: Do you know?
DM: You haven't, like, scouted?
Kenzo: We haven't been to Drankor yet, no.
DM: His tomb is pretty obvious.
Kenzo: Yeah?
Delwath: But his tomb is not where his, uh-
Wellby: Phylactery is
Unknown: ... phylactery is.
Unknown: That would be pretty tough.
DM: Oh, you want to kill him,
DM: not just lock him up?
Unknown: If you can.
Wellby: Yeah, how would we lock him up?
DM: I don't know. Retie the knots.
DM: Aren't you magic?
Kenzo: Eh, not that way.
Wellby: Yeah, no.
Kenzo: I mean, maybe Rai could help us.
DM: Oh, well, that's much harder.
Kenzo: Why is that much harder?
DM: Well, I don't know where his phylactery is.
Kenzo: I... But, well, that's why we get the last piece of jade and then we figure out where the phylactery is.
Unknown: [laughs] Have you been listening to our story?
DM: Oh, you think Rai knows where his phylactery is?
DM: Oh, maybe he does, actually.
DM: Hmm.
DM: Interesting.
Kenzo: Can you help us find Rai?
DM: I looked.
Kenzo: Yeah, in Drankor, huh? Couldn't find him.
DM: He never came back.
Wellby: Hmm.
DM: He went off with the monks.
Wellby: Oh, the monks.
DM: Wait, that was your friends who convinced him to do that?
Kenzo: I think Rai was the one that was convincing them.
DM: Oh, that's possible.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: The other way around with the convincing.
DM: I know he did. Like, they had a few little successes.
Kenzo: Successes doing what?
DM: Cleaning up the Seeds of Chaos.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Then they went for the big one.
DM: I thought it was a mistake.
Kenzo: Does Cha'mut have other children?
Unknown: If only he'd listened.
DM: Yeah, if only Rai... Rai never...
DM: He didn't listen to me.
DM: Damn it.
Kenzo: What, what, what, what, what was your advice to Rai?
Kenzo: What were you trying to get him to do?
DM: Don't go to the gi- the biggest, giantest Seed of Chaos and try and fix it in Isingue.
DM: That seems like a stupid thing to do.
Seeker: That's how all those, those monks were lost, presumably.
DM: Mm.
Delwath: Remember, that's the acidic ooze that we flew over.
Kenzo: What is?
DM: Oh.
Kenzo: Oh.
Wellby: Yeah. No, I think you were right.
Unknown: [laughs] Dimitar's-
DM: This one's smart
Seeker: ... Dimitar's got some insights into how the world works.
Delwath: But maybe after we kill Apollyon we should go figure it out.
Seeker: Well, we should see what Dimitar says about that.
Kenzo: Yeah. Wait, but, yeah, but, but what were you trying to tell Rai?
Unknown: So your, your, your advice to Rai was-
Unknown: It did hurt our ship after all
DM: ... don't go. It's the biggest place of all.
Unknown: We gotta take revenge
Unknown: It's true.
DM: But he was pretty sure he could do it.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: Huh.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: Shemut has other children?
DM: I don't know.
Kenzo: How do you know this is Shemut's daughter?
Unknown: You haven't heard her brag?
Kenzo: What's brag?
Unknown: When did you talk to her?
DM: I didn't talk to her. You didn't ask it.
DM: You just never bothered to ask.
DM: Like-
Kenzo: Ask who?
DM: Any of the stupid dragonets flying around.
DM: I am... He's, like, imitating somebody.
DM: I am Ra'ghemdros, daughter of Shemut.
DM: I am the Light Stealer and the Final Shadow, the Devourer of Drankor, known as the Eternal Night.
DM: She's not shy about it.
Kenzo: She's pretty boastful, huh?
Unknown: Those are some good names though.
Kenzo: Yeah?
Unknown: Uh, we haven't seen the ending though.
Kenzo: Yeah, we have. We just, we just haven't been there that long.
Kenzo: We've only been here for half a day. So, so okay, so she's Shemut's daughter.
Kenzo: She's here on some task that Shemut
Kenzo: has put her to.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Nominally.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: And you don't know what that task is.
Delwath: Hey, did the hobgoblin wizard who's in the...
Unknown: She was against Shemut, right?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: You know who might be an ally killing Shemut's daughter?
Seeker: Is the hobgoblin wi- wizard we have trapped in the mirror?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: She's not gonna go back in the mirror again after what's happened.
DM: No, of course not.
Seeker: No, her... What she gets in re- in return is...
Unknown: Well, no, we can't give her the island.
Wellby: We can't exactly stop her from taking [laughs].
Delwath: We could, we could try to kill her though.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: Double cross her.
DM: Maybe a bad idea.
Unknown: I, yeah, that's-
DM: But, like, there's something here.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: But she was an ally of Shemut?
DM: Enemy.
Kenzo: Enemy.
DM: But she was trapped by...
DM: She tried to trap Shemut in the mirror, and he was like, "No, no, no, you go in the mirror."
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: Oh, maybe we could s- maybe she knows about Ra'ghemdros.
DM: We could talk to her.
Unknown: That'd be a great person to talk to.
Unknown: I think it's a good idea.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, uh-
Delwath: She might help us just to see Ra'ghemdros die, even in not being freed.
Wellby: But also, what if she's been biding her time this entire time, and, like, could have left the prison at any moment, and now we take her out and talk to her and-
Unknown: We're not taking her out to talk to her.
Unknown: We're talking to her in the mirror.
DM: No, we can talk to her in the mirror.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: I, I think we should talk to her.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. But let's just... We're, th- we're talking to Dimitaur now, right?
Kenzo: So what else do we do- want to learn from Dimitaur?
Kenzo: Can you help us find Rai
Kenzo: now? 'Cause we're going to Drankor next after this, almost certainly.
DM: I do not wanna go back to Drankor.
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: But you know it pretty well.
DM: I do.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: One favor.
Kenzo: Maybe you can help us with a map.
Delwath: Hm. I was gonna say, can we spend, like, two hours
Delwath: digging through everything he knows about Drankor?
DM: You can, but you can't hear it now because I haven't made it up.
Unknown: Yes, I know. That's what I was just gonna say.
Kenzo: That's fine.
DM: Um-
Delwath: I mean, would he... What, why don't we just, like, c- c- could you tell us everything you know?
DM: Yeah, I could tell you some stuff.
Kenzo: Look, here's the basics.
Kenzo: We get the last piece of jade.
Kenzo: Hopefully, that tells us where the phylactery is.
Kenzo: Almost certainly it's gonna be in Drankor, and then we're gonna go and try and destroy the phylactery.
Kenzo: We expect it's gonna be really hard going there.
Kenzo: Is Drankor now, like, is it, like, some haunted, like, fucked up place that's gonna, like, try to kill us at every turn?
DM: It wasn't really like that when Rai was there.
DM: I bet it's gotten a lot worse.
Kenzo: Since when?
Unknown: Since Rai left.
DM: Since Rai left.
Kenzo: Like 39 years ago?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I couldn't stay much,
DM: like, only a few months.
DM: I only stayed there a few months waiting for him, and it got dark and scary, and there was this, like, aura of fear that radiated out through the whole place coming
DM: from Apollyon's tomb. And every morning, I woke up wanting to run away, and eventually I did.
Kenzo: Hm.
DM: And I'm not sure I could go back.
Kenzo: Yeah, it doesn't sound like a good place.
Kenzo: Um-
Delwath: Collect immunity to fear artifacts.
Kenzo: Or a feast.
Unknown: I think one of the binding-
Unknown: Or Rizwin
Unknown: ... things can
Unknown: be Rizwin. Or Rizwin.
Seeker: I wonder how Rizwin's doing. Oh, well.
Kenzo: So, so-
Unknown: Who knows?
Kenzo: Okay. Anyways, yeah, we appreciate any insights you have 'cause I think we're gonna have to go there.
Kenzo: It sounds pretty scary, but we are gonna try to go there.
Kenzo: And when we go there, if Rai is still there, if, do you have any tips on if we wanna try to find him?
Kenzo: Would you want, would you want his hand back?
DM: I mean,
DM: if I took your hand from you and then showed up, would you want it back?
Kenzo: How do we give it back to him?
DM: I don't know. Like, maybe you could take it and hand it to him.
Unknown: Hand it to him?
Kenzo: Here he is.
DM: This one's got it.
Unknown: Nice.
Kenzo: So, so, so-
Unknown: Nice
Kenzo: ... but yeah, but do you, any, any, any ideas how to find him?
Unknown: Do, do we even know he's findable?
Unknown: I mean, we don't actually-
Kenzo: We're asking. I mean, I don't know.
Unknown: Didn't Dimitaur say that-
Kenzo: Would we even know if he was dead? No, he said he d- can't ever die.
Kenzo: The part is something, somewhere-
Delwath: I mean, he said he couldn't find him and he went looking, and he also said he doesn't think Rai can ever die.
DM: But he wasn't in... Dimitaur could not find him in Drankor.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Maybe he was, like, trapped for a while and then came back to Drankor somehow.
Kenzo: But what, what I'm trying to say is when you're, when you're looking for some kind of weird, you know, immortal sorcerer or whatever, like, does he respond to anything or, like, is there anything that-
DM: I don't know. Send your, like, spirit dog after him.
Kenzo: Is that what you try to do when you find him?
Kenzo: Like, what do you do when you try to find him?
Delwath: Actually, that's not a bad idea. Why didn't we think of that?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I don't know. You're just not as smart as he, I guess.
Kenzo: I mean, we're clearly not, but, like, any, any other tips, any other advice for, for finding him?
DM: I mean,
DM: the last place I know he was was Isingay.
Kenzo: Isingay?
Unknown: That's where that acidic ooze is
Kenzo: Huh?
Unknown: When we're all... The whole...
Unknown: It was like-
Delwath: Remember we flew, we flew over Isingue in Vincharna.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And we went down to investigate 'cause it looked cool, and a tendril of acidic ooze-
Unknown: Yes, totally. I totally remember that
DM: Punched a hole in the-
Unknown: That's the last place where I was?
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: That's when we went with the monks to try and-
Delwath: That is apparently where he was trying to heal the land.
Delwath: That's the seat of chaos. He was trying to get rid of it.
Seeker: So that was a portal or something.
Kenzo: Fuck.
Seeker: But, and all those monks basically died or didn't come back anyway.
DM: They either died or they got scattered around the planes when they were...
DM: when the chaos happened.
Wellby: What do you, what do you think the odds are of killing that dragon?
DM: I couldn't.
DM: I don't know.
DM: You're, like, not too shabby from what I've seen.
DM: I mean, you certainly avoided my trap neatly.
DM: [sighs] But, like...
Seeker: What would it take to lure her out of her lair, though?
Wellby: Yeah. What would get her out?
Kenzo: Yeah. We, we don't want to fight her in there.
Seeker: We've heard that she l-loves shiny things.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: But [coughs]...
Wellby: Why would she kill you if she knew you were on the island?
Wellby: 'Cause of your, like, escape attempt that you led?
Kenzo: Bad influence on the other dragonets.
DM: Yeah. She thinks I'm a bad influence.
Delwath: I mean, she might have a hatred of Rai who killed her father.
Wellby: Yeah, that's fair.
DM: I think she just likes her little simple empire here.
DM: She doesn't like anybody who kinda
DM: speaks up.
Unknown: So you're saying her, um,
Seeker: ambitions aren't as grandiose as Cha'mutte's.
DM: I see no reason why she couldn't leave this island if she wanted to.
Kenzo: So she's s- she's serving some kind of function here that's useful, of use to her deceased dad.
Kenzo: Um, if you were us and, uh,
Kenzo: you needed to
Kenzo: get that piece of jade back from the dragon,
Kenzo: any advice?
DM: If I were you?
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I'd pick an easier quest.
Kenzo: Eh.
Kenzo: Let's say you had to do this one, though.
DM: [laughs] Good.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, Dimitar.
Kenzo: Does, um,
Delwath: she keep her deals for the most part?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: You think she would trade?
DM: She might. I mean, she might just, like, say, "I'll kill you and take your stuff anyway."
Kenzo: But that'd be fine with us.
Wellby: That's okay.
Delwath: Isn't that kind of the opposite of keeping your deals?
DM: Uh... [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: She-
Unknown: When you said yes, did you mean no?
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: No, no, no, no, no.
Kenzo: No.
DM: She's never, uh, she's never taken away a tower she gave to a dragonet.
Kenzo: Hm.
DM: But, you know,
DM: who knows? Many of them might go in there and be like, "Hey, here's some stuff," and she says, "I don't like you, so I'll just take that stuff."
Seeker: And she sometimes kills them to prove a point or to make an example of them.
DM: Yeah, sometimes. I mean,
DM: gotta keep a little bit of an aura of fear.
Unknown: But she's consistent, at least.
DM: Patten.
Kenzo: Was she, um...
Delwath: Do you know anything about her relationship with her father?
DM: Not really.
DM: I mean,
DM: all I know is
DM: she's quite boastful and has told many, many dragonets that she is the daughter of Cha'mutte.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: They've told me, the few who come up here every now and then.
Delwath: Have they been here since, uh...
Delwath: How long have the dragonets been here? Do you know?
Unknown: Oh, you, you didn't know?
DM: [coughs] You guys, like, don't really do your research, do you?
Kenzo: We just got here. Come on. Cut us a break.
Kenzo: Cut us a little... Give us a little break here.
Delwath: I... They said forever, which is clearly not true.
DM: Yeah. They're... We were, we were here...
DM: My people
DM: were on Hkar with the humans.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: We came across.
Delwath: Didn't you just say you didn't realize there were so many of your people here?
DM: I didn't know they survived the plague.
DM: The story that I've fled, like many of us fled to the Feywild, to the Far East, all sorts of distant places when Drancor fell.
DM: Well, even before Drancor fell.
DM: A few,
DM: you know, took in with the Polyron, and a few took in with Cha'mutte, but most of us just got out of dodge.
Kenzo: Hm.
DM: But we were there all the way from the beginning.
DM: I just thought they were all slaughtered on this island.
DM: If they say forever, I think they, like, mean it, probably since the island was made.
Kenzo: Who made the island?
DM: I don't know, like, wizards.
Kenzo: Like human wizards?
Wellby: Wizards don't, uh, don't do your research, huh?
DM: Oh, well, do you have an answer for me?
DM: Do you know who made the island?
Wellby: Yes, but it's a secret.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: I don't like this one.
Unknown: [coughs] Yeah, I don't know.
DM: Like, there were all sorts of wizards back in the day.
DM: They could do all kinds of things.
DM: You didn't hear Rai's stories?
DM: Oh, wait, how would you hear Rai's stories?
Kenzo: Yeah. Never met the guy.
Kenzo: Just had some weird rumors about him.
DM: Yeah, he could probably have made this island.
DM: Well, maybe not alone.
Kenzo: He didn't... But he didn't make it, though.
DM: No. It's way older than him.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hm.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah, they could do like, you know, Hkar, with like magic stuff.
Kenzo: Is it, is it true that this island walked?
DM: I, I think so.
Seeker: Where did it come f- walk from?
DM: Hkar.
Unknown: Weren't you listening? [laughs]
DM: Yeah. This guy gets it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: This one looks like an absent-minded professor.
DM: I think that's what I'm gonna call him.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Dr. Absent-Minded.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Yeah, that's about right.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Kenzo: Uh, any idea who started the plague?
Unknown: Shemuhitte?
DM: Shemuhitte.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Are you not listening?
Kenzo: Eh.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Eh-
Kenzo: So the plague came here too?
DM: I mean, Shemuhitte and Apollyon hated each other.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: His... Like he had some crappy tower.
DM: Well, it probably wasn't that crappy actually.
DM: It's kind of crappy now.
Kenzo: Apollyon did?
DM: I mean, nobody's been here.
Unknown: Out in the west.
DM: What, where you hide the forges?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's where the forge is.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: So is Shemuhitte's daughter's mission to d- protect the divine forge against Apollyon's return?
DM: Maybe.
DM: I know she doesn't like Apollyon.
Unknown: Would she help us-
Delwath: Yeah, see, I was going there earlier
Unknown: ... to defeat him?
Kenzo: Keep him imprisoned?
DM: Maybe.
Unknown: Like
Unknown: there's an argument that we just-
DM: If she genuinely thought you could kill Apollyon, she might be like, "Hey, go do it."
Seeker: [sighs] Maybe we could even forge something
Unknown: to help us.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Kenzo: If only we had an artificer.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Or to help us find the phylactery especially.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, there is the, we team up with Shemuhitte's daughter and an evil hobgoblin wizard to kill Apollyon and let the consequences be somebody else's problem.
DM: Wait, the evil hobgoblin wizard is against Shemuhitte.
Delwath: Oh, oh, oh, right. Never mind.
Unknown: We gotta pick one.
Kenzo: My enemy's friend is my friend's enemy's enemy.
Unknown: Ah! [laughs]
Delwath: We either team up with the evil hobgoblin wizard to kill Shemuhitte's daughter.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Or we team... But she'd probably go join up with Apollyon.
Delwath: Or we team up with Shemuhitte's daughter to kill Apollyon.
Unknown: I like that one.
Seeker: Well, could you get us an introduction?
Unknown: No, I wouldn't-
Delwath: Have you been listening? [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] But have you been over to the west where Apollyon's tower was?
DM: I will be honest.
Wellby: Is this a change?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That scares me.
Kenzo: What? Why?
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: [coughs] So you've been there and it terrifies you, or you're just too scared to go?
DM: Too scared to go.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: You... Th- th-
Delwath: Weren't you listening to the whole story of Apollyon and the fear?
DM: Apollyon, like super evil.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Oh, yeah.
DM: Uh-
Kenzo: He visits. I've seen him.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I've made eye contact with the guy.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I have a, I have a, I have a task for you.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hit me. Go ahead.
DM: If you are a super e- evil wizard who had built a tower on top of a powerful divine forge, would you leave magical defenses or would you leave it completely undefended so anybody
DM: could just walk in without doing...
DM: without any care in the world?
Kenzo: Magical defenses.
Unknown: Bingo.
Kenzo: Yes.
Unknown: Why do you think I don't wanna go?
Kenzo: Magical defenses.
DM: Yes. You got it in one.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: We- we're good at that though.
Unknown: I mean,
Unknown: yeah.
Unknown: Or so we think.
Unknown: We haven't been
Seeker: completely annihilated as a group.
Unknown: So maybe you should go there.
Seeker: Yes. Tangling with those.
Kenzo: Hmm. Hmm.
Delwath: All right. What we should do is stay up for another hour to pick his brain about Drankor, meta write that down that we picked his brain about Drankor.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Take a long rest, and then either go to Apollyon's tower
Unknown: or-
Unknown: Yeah. To negotiate with the dragon
Delwath: ... hatch a plan, which we need to decide what it would be.
Delwath: But it's 2:20. I don't know if you wanted to take a break.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. I actually, I actually need to go do, do my call here.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Let's take a break.
Kenzo: It's the perfect, perfect time.
Unknown: This is a good time to.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: So, I mean, let's...
Unknown: That was really fun.
Unknown: Let's see-
Kenzo: Well, and I, I thought, yeah, w- we wanna hear some more ride stories too.
DM: We can, we can do a little more Dimitar over the campfire.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. We can do that. We can do that like later.
Unknown: A flashback.
Kenzo: Like, like a flashback or like...
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: We can do a flashback.
Wellby: Yeah. So the choice when we c- reconvene is do we go to the dragon and start with negotiation of some kind to be figured out or do we go to Apollyon's tower and see what's going on there?
Kenzo: So this is the thing-
Delwath: Or do we just decide we should try and kill the dragon possibly by consulting with our hobgoblin wizard who's trapped?
Kenzo: That's what we should do next. We should, we should consult with the hobgoblin.
Kenzo: No matter what, we should talk to the hobgoblin wizard next.
Unknown: That's true. Actually, that's true.
Kenzo: Just to learn, just to get as much from her as we can.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: 'Cause this is the thing,
Kenzo: the dragon,
Kenzo: like we don't know yet the weird purpose that it is staying here for.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Which is gonna be important and maybe potentially linked to whatever's going on in the west.
Kenzo: So if we just go... So we need to s- we just need to understand a little bit more about the dynamics here 'cause there c- it could be that there's like a cool item or a thing that's in Apollyon's tower that the dragon can't get
Kenzo: to, that if we got it, she would willing, be willing to trade with us or, you know...
Wellby: Yeah. Or when Apollyon's prison breaks, this is important for some reason that she has to defend it or-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... something else.
Kenzo: Well, we just need to learn a little bit more if we can figure it out.
Unknown: Yeah. I mean,
Unknown: I think
Delwath: that if we wanted to negotiate,
Unknown: it sounds like
Unknown: she would probably...
Delwath: The challenge would be more than anything convincing her that we're not bullshitting when we're actually saying we're gonna kill Apollyon, right?
Unknown: Anyway, let's take a-
Wellby: This feels like a good night's rest. Yeah.
Unknown: Let's, let's take a break.
Wellby: When are we reconvening?